<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>

<?Fm Condition DITA-Topicmeta Red NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Prolog AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Comment AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_SYSTEM_HIDEELEMENT AsIs NO_OVERRIDE hide?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_TRACK_CHANGES_ADDED Forest%20Green SINGLE_UNDERLINE show?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_TRACK_CHANGES_DELETED Red STRIKETHROUGH show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Data AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>

<?Fm BoolCondExpr "DITA-Data" State 0?>


<?Fm TrackChange Off PreviewState PREVIEW_OFF_TRACK_CHANGE?>
<topic id = "id2684760c-070f-4322-b3da-dd3ae20db3fa"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>1.00.26 - 31 August 2008</title>
<body><section><title outputclass = "h3">New Features</title><dl>
<dlentry><dt>Search in Files command matches on partial attribute
values.</dt>
<dd>The Search in Files command now allows for matching on partial
attribute values. This is especially useful for locating elements
that have multiple values applied to their filtering attributes. </dd></dlentry></dl></section>
<section><title outputclass = "h3">Bug Fixes</title><dl><dlentry><dt>Apply
Ditaval as Conditions command applies overlapping conditions.</dt>
<dd>The Apply Ditaval as Conditions command now applies overlapping
conditions as required by attribute settings.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Generate Book from Map no longer saves XML files as
FM.</dt>
<dd>In rare circumstances the Generate Book from Map command would
save the XML file as a binary FM file making it impossible to continue.
This no longer happens.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>WMF images are now properly handled.</dt>
<dd>When adding a WMF image, it was not properly shrinkwrapped and
the href value was not set until file save. WMF files are now handled
the same as other image types</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Windows Vista problems fixed.</dt>
<dd>On Windows Vista, inserting an xref no longer causes FM to crash. </dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Element templates must be closed to be used.</dt>
<dd>If you try to use an element template for a new file when the
element template is open, you now receive a warning that you must
close the template before it can be used. </dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Build Map from Outline handles invalid para styles.</dt>
<dd>If a paragraph style in the outline document references a style
that doesn’t map to a topic type FM will no longer crash. </dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Conref problems resolved.</dt>
<dd>A conref to an xref will no longer cause FM to hang. Conrefs
can now be made to simpletable elements (and related table types). </dd></dlentry></dl></section></body></topic>
