<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [
]>
<?dtall dict="FrameMaker\Structure\xml"?><topic id = "id0838A0Q605Z"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Installing a DITA-FMx Update</title>
<shortdesc status = "changed">Basic options for upgrading your DITA-FMx
installation to the latest point release.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-03-08"/>
<revised modified = "2017-10-10"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "changed"><p status = "changed">To reinstall or update
DITA-FMx over an existing installation, you’ve got two basic options.</p>
<dl status = "new"><dlentry><dt status = "new">Quick and simple,
but unable to revert to the previous version</dt>
<dd status = "new">When installing an interim update, or you don’t
care about being able to roll back to the previous version, this
approach is for you.</dd>
<dd status = "new">Just run the installer. No backup or uninstall
is required. The installer will overwrite all like-named files in
the <filepath status = "changed">DITA-FMx-2</filepath> folder. It
will not overwrite the <filepath>ditafmx.ini</filepath> file, so
your settings will not be lost.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry status = "new"><dt status = "new">Fresh install, and able
to revert to the previous version</dt>
<dd status = "changed">If you’d like to get a “fresh” install, you
should rename the existing <filepath status = "new">DITA-FMx-2</filepath> folder
(perhaps to something like <filepath status = "changed">DITA-FMx-2.&lt;oldversion></filepath>)
before running the new installer. This will give you a completely
new set of files, and will let you compare the new files to the
old files and allow you to “roll back” to a previous version if
needed. If you choose this approach, you will need to manually migrate
any manually entered settings in the <filepath>ditafmx.ini</filepath> file.
In particular, you’ll need to migrate the info in the Registration
section. Just copy and paste the entire Registration section into
the new <filepath>ditafmx.ini</filepath> file after it is created,
then restart FrameMaker. (Otherwise, you’ll need to enter your registration
information and auth code in order to initialize the application.)</dd></dlentry></dl>
<p>After installing the update, you may want to copy the new structure
applications to the <filepath>FrameMaker\Structure\xml\</filepath> folder
so you can take advantage of any changes that have been made. The
DITA-FMx installer does not install the new structure applications,
they are provided in a ZIP file in the <filepath status = "changed">DITA-FMx-2</filepath> folder.
If you’re using your own custom applications, you should review
the DITA-FMx Revision History, so you can integrate any structure
application updates. In particular, you should consider using the
updated XSLT scripts for the Book application to take advantage of
any fixes to the book-build processing.</p>
<note status = "changed">If you’re installing an update on <ph conref="ditafmx_shared.xml#common/winvers_new"></ph>,
keep in mind that the user-editable INI files are in the “app data”
area not in the Program Files area.</note>
<note type = "important" otherprops = "fm120">If you’re installing
an update on FM12, due to a core problem in FrameMaker, you must
manually delete the <filepath>ModalDialogPosition.ini</filepath> file
to allow updated DITA-FMx dialogs to display at their proper size.
This INI file can be found in “%appdata%\Adobe\FrameMaker\12”.</note></body></topic>
