<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "id067FF700BPN"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Update References</title>
<shortdesc>Updates the content of topicrefs, conrefs, xrefs, or
links.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "UNK"/>
<revised modified = "2008-02-24"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-30"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p>Depending on the type of file currently being edited, this
dialog provides options for updating references in the file. If
a DITA map is active, you have the option to update the selected
topicref or all topicrefs in the file. If a DITA topic file is active,
you can update xrefs, links, and/or conrefs.</p>
<fig audience = "web"><title>DITA-FMx Update References dialog box</title><image
href="images/updaterefs.png" align="left" placement="break"  otherprops
= "fmdpi:110"/></fig>
<section><title>References in DITA Maps</title><p>Existing topicref
elements can be updated so the label text reflects changes in the referenced
file’s title. To update an existing topicref, select the label and
choose the <uicontrol>Update References</uicontrol> command. The <uicontrol>Update
References</uicontrol> command also lets you update all topicrefs
in the DITA map reflect changes in the referenced files’ titles. This
command honors the setting of the topicref’s locktitle attribute;
if locktitle is set to ‘yes’ the navtitle text is not updated.</p><dl>
<dlentry><dt>Update Selected Topicref</dt>
<dd>Updates the content of the selected topicref (only if a topicref
is selected).</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Update All Topicrefs in File</dt>
<dd>Updates all of the topicrefs in the current file to reflect
any changes to titles in referenced files.</dd></dlentry></dl></section>
<section><title>References in DITA Topics</title><dl><dlentry><dt>Update
All Conrefs in File</dt>
<dd>Updates all of the conrefs in the current file to reflect any
changes to the source content.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Update All Xrefs in File</dt>
<dd>Updates all of the xrefs and links in the current file to reflect
any changes to titles in referenced files.</dd></dlentry></dl></section></body></topic>
