<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>

<?Fm Condition DITA-Topicmeta Red NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Prolog AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Comment AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_SYSTEM_HIDEELEMENT AsIs NO_OVERRIDE hide?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_TRACK_CHANGES_ADDED Forest%20Green SINGLE_UNDERLINE show?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_TRACK_CHANGES_DELETED Red STRIKETHROUGH show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Data AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>

<?Fm BoolCondExpr "DITA-Data" State 0?>


<?Fm TrackChange Off PreviewState PREVIEW_OFF_TRACK_CHANGE?>
<topic id = "id0844H0YL05Z"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Prepare Variables</title>
<shortdesc>Saves variable names to attribute values so they can
be rebuilt after the map to book conversion.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-04-04"/>
<revised modified = "2008-04-19"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p>FrameMaker variables are saved to XML as entities, and
will round-trip fine in and out of Frame (as long as they are named
properly). However, any variables that are processed by the <uicontrol>Generate
Book from Map</uicontrol> command are flattened (converted to text)
because entities do not survive XSLT processing. This command was
developed as a way to work around this limitation. </p>
<p>Before running the <uicontrol>Generate Book from Map</uicontrol> command,
run the <uicontrol>Prepare Variables</uicontrol> command on all
files that contain FrameMaker variables. This wraps each variable
in a <codeph>ph</codeph> element and assigns the variable name to
the keyref attribute using the format “fmvar:VARNAME” (where VARNAME
is the name of the variable). After conversion to a book and chapter
files, you can run the <uicontrol>Rebuild Variables</uicontrol> command
to rebuild live variables from the data stored in the ph elements.</p>
<p>You can run the <uicontrol>Prepare Variables</uicontrol> command
individually on each DITA file, or you can use the <uicontrol>Build
Workbook from Map</uicontrol> command to create a “workbook” from
which you can process all of the files at once. Before running the <uicontrol>Prepare
Variables</uicontrol> command on the workbook, you must first open
all of the files with the <uicontrol>Open All XML Files in Book</uicontrol> command.</p>
<p>It is fine to run this command multiple times on the same files
or variables, so you may just want to run the command after entering
a variable or before saving a file.</p>
<note type = "important">If you use the <uicontrol>Prepare Variables</uicontrol> command
and feel inclined to set attributes on the <codeph>ph</codeph> elements
that wrap the variables, don’t do it. The <codeph>ph</codeph> wrappers
are temporary and are deleted each time the command is run. If you
want to apply filtering or other attributes to variables, wrap them
in a <codeph>ph</codeph> element and apply the attributes on that
element.</note>
<p>The DITA-FMx Options dialog offers the <uicontrol>Auto Prepare
Variables on Save</uicontrol> option. If this option is enabled,
the <uicontrol>Prepare Variables</uicontrol> command is run each
time you save the document. This may allow you to skip running this
command on a workbook before generating the final book file.</p></body></topic>
