<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [
]>
<?dtall dict="autonum"?><?dtall dict="FMx"?><?dtall dict="hazardstatement"?><topic
    id = "id12ec2684-05f9-4d85-8f60-3540edc24e63"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Authoring Hazard Statements</title>
<shortdesc>In order to make them easier to visualize, DITA-FMx performs
minor adjustments to <synph outputclass = "element">hazardstatement</synph> elements
when authoring.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "2017-10-03"/>
<revised modified = "2017-11-10"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p>The DITA model places the <synph outputclass = "element">hazardsymbol</synph> element
at the end of the <synph outputclass = "element">hazardstatement</synph> model.
This can make for a somewhat odd-looking layout when authoring.
The default DITA-FMx publishing process wraps this model in a special hazard
table to make it all look right, but that can’t be easily done for
authoring.</p>
<fig><image href="images/hazard-topic-struct.png" align="left" placement="break"
 outputclass = "fmdpi:120"/></fig>
<p>As of DITA-FMx 2.0.06, special processing of <synph
    outputclass = "element">hazardstatement</synph> elements while authoring,
is done if the Process Hazardstatement Elements option is enabled
in the Authoring Options dialog.</p>
<p>The default DITA-FMx Topic application, indents the <synph
    outputclass = "element">hazardstatement</synph> elements which
allows the <synph outputclass = "element">hazardsymbol</synph> image
to be moved into the space to the left of the hazard information.
The Max Symbol Width setting in the Authoring Options dialog controls
the maximum image width; be sure to set this to a value that fits
in the available space.</p>
<fig><image href="images/hazard-topic.png" align="left" placement="break"
 outputclass = "fmdpi:120"/></fig>
<p>The hazard type label (“ATTENTION:” in the image above) is controlled
by the autonum prefix of the paragraph tag assigned to the <synph
    outputclass = "element">typeofhazard</synph> element. This paragraph
tag is set based on the <synph outputclass = "attribute">type</synph> attribute
of the <synph outputclass = "element">hazardstatement</synph> element.
The position of the <synph outputclass = "element">hazardsymbol</synph> image
is set when the image is inserted. It’s also updated on file save,
so it may not look quite right after adding more content to the
hazard statement until you save. If multiple <synph
    outputclass = "element">hazardsymbol</synph> elements are included,
only the first is placed in the indented space; the rest are added
after the last <synph outputclass = "element">messagepanel</synph> element.</p>
<p>Setting the <synph outputclass = "attribute">align</synph> attribute
of the <synph outputclass = "element">hazardsymbol</synph> element
controls the horizontal placement within the indented area as well
as in the published output.</p>
<note>A prefix/suffix on the <synph outputclass = "element">hazardstatement</synph> element
is not supported by the default processing.</note></body></topic>
