<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="FrameMaker\DITA"?><?dtall dict="ProductA"?><?dtall dict="ProductB"?><topic
    id = "id083DA0A0WY4"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Set Attributes</title>
<shortdesc>Provides a quick and easy way to set attribute values
and provide custom project-specific attribute values.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-03-13"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-09"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p status = "changed">The Set Attributes command displays
a modeless dialog that lets you easily set the attribute values
on selected elements. Attribute names are displayed in a listbox
on the left of the dialog, and when one is selected, an appropriate
form field is displayed on the right for you to enter or select
the value to apply. Use the popup list box in the lower left of
the dialog to set the size of the dialog. The larger dialogs allow
selection of more values.</p>
<fig audience = "web"><title>DITA-FMx Set Attributes dialog box,
single value selection</title><image href="images/setattributes-choices.png"
align="left" placement="break"  otherprops = "fmdpi:110"/></fig>
<p status = "changed">Depending on the underlying attribute type
(Choice, String, Strings, Integer, Integers, Real, Reals, IDReference,
IDReferences, and UniqueID), as defined in the EDD, the attribute
values display in a different type of field. For a Choice attribute,
the values specified in the EDD by the Choices element are displayed
in a scrolling list box. For the Strings, Integers, Reals, and IDReferences
attribute types, the values specified in the EDD by the “Default”
elements is displayed as an array of checkboxes (up to 10 in the
small dialog, 20 in the medium dialog, and 40 in the large dialog),
allowing you to select one or more values. All other attribute types
are displayed in a simple text box. The checkboxes are particularly
useful for managing the DITA filtering attributes (platform, product,
audience, and otherprops).</p>
<p>Because the dialog is modeless, you can leave it open and whenever
desired, select an element and apply new attribute values. In addition
to the main DITA-FMx menu, the Set Attributes command is available
from the context (right-click) menus.</p>
<p>The Set Attributes command provides a feature that lets you extend
the values displayed for specific attributes, by allowing these
to be specified in a text file. It also lets you specify different
predefined attribute values for different projects. This mechanism
lets you associate a <i>filtering group</i> name with a file system
path. When editing a DITA file that is within the specified path,
the values associated with that group are displayed with those defined
in the EDD. These groups and their associated attribute names and
possible values are defined in an INI file named (by default) <filepath>FilterGroups.ini</filepath> that
is created in the user’s DITA-FMx folder (<menucascade><uicontrol>DITA-FMx</uicontrol>
<uicontrol>Open DITA-FMx Folder</uicontrol></menucascade>). You
can edit this file by choosing the <uicontrol>Edit INI</uicontrol> button
in the Set Attributes dialog.</p>
<p>The following sample filtering groups file defines two groups
named ProductA and ProductB (these are both defined as an attribute
of type “Strings” in the EDD). When you edit a DITA file that is
in the path specified by group ProductA, selecting the product attribute
will offer the three products listed (in addition to any already defined
in the EDD) as options. Likewise, selecting audience or platform
will offer those items as options.</p>
<codeblock status = "changed">[General] 
ProductA=C:\projects\product-a 
ProductB=C:\projects\product-b 
 
[ProductA] 
product=ProdALite|ProdAFull|ProdASimple 
audience=Novice|Expert|Admin 
platform=windows|mac|linux|unix 
outputclass=style1|style2|style3|style4|style5|style6 
 
[ProductB] 
product=ProdBLite|ProdBFull 
audience=User|Developer|Admin 
platform=windows|mac|linux|unix 
outputclass=style1|style2|style3|style4|style5|style6</codeblock>
<fig audience = "web"><title>DITA-FMx Set Attributes dialog box,
multiple value selection</title><image href="images/setattributes-strings.png"
align="left" placement="break"  otherprops = "fmdpi:110"/></fig>
<p>This mechanism can also be used for attributes defined as a type
of “String” to predefine mutually exclusive attribute values similar
to the attribute type of “Choice.” In the previous example, selecting
the outputclass attribute (defined as a “String” in the EDD) from
the list, would display a scrolling list box with the style names
available for selection.</p>
<p>There are three “INI-Only” parameters that can be used to enhance
the functionality of this command.</p>
<dl><dlentry><dt>SetAttrStrings</dt>
<dd><p>Specifies an alternate file to use as the filtering groups
INI file. Useful to define a shared file at a network location.</p></dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>SetAttrIgnore</dt>
<dd><p>Specifies the attributes to ignore (and not display) in the
Set Attributes dialog.</p></dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>SetAttrStringsDefault</dt>
<dd><p>Specifies the “default” value that is ignored when displaying
the list of defaults.</p></dd></dlentry></dl>
<p>To modify these settings, you must manually edit the <filepath
conref = "ditafmx_shared.xml#common/ditafm-ini" class = "+ topic/ph
sw-d/filepath "></filepath> file and update (or add) these values
to the INIOnly section. For more information see <xref href = "ditafmx_ref_inionly.xml#id067FF8008E9"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref>.</p></body></topic>
