<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "idffd51b4f-bdc6-404e-b8cb-53907629e66f"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Best Practice for Book Assembly</title>
<shortdesc status = "new">Tips and information that applies to both
maps and bookmaps.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "2009-03-07"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-28"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "changed"><p>When setting up a <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">map</synph> or <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">bookmap</synph> that will be used to
define a book-like deliverable (either as a PDF or online format
that breaks topics into sections or chapters), it is common to create
a root map with submaps (or chapter-maps). The root map would, at
a minimum, contain <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">topicref</synph> (or <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">chapter</synph>, <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">appendix</synph>, etc.) elements
that point to each submap (chapter). If your root map is a <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">bookmap</synph>, it would
also contain the <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">frontmatter</synph> and <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">backmatter</synph> along
with the appropriate child elements. It might also contain a relationship
table, but depending on your structure, you might want to maintain
relationship tables in the submaps.</p>
<p>The submaps should be standard DITA maps (not a bookmap). If
you are using the default DITA-FMx XSLT import script that is provided
with the Book application, your chapter maps should contain a single
root <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">topicref</synph> element
which defines the chapter title and any optional content that would
appear before the first H1-level heading in the generated FM file.
Any topicref elements that are children of the root topicref become
the H1, H2, and so on, headings within the chapter.</p>
<note status = "new">When using the default DITA-FMx XSLT import
script, the use of a submap adds no hierarchy or topics to the generated
FM files. A map should be thought of as purely an authoring convenience.
All headings in the resulting FM files are created from titles in
DITA topics. Currently, the <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">topichead</synph> and <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">topicgroup</synph> elements are ignored
in the book-build process, as are any attributes applied to those elements.</note>
<p>If you want to be able to use the titles from the submaps as
the chapter titles, you’ll need to modify the XSLT import script
to pull that content from the map and insert it into the proper
location in the output.</p>
<p>This method of creating chapter maps makes it very convenient
to assign a “chapter” to a specific writer. Note that it is perfectly
reasonable to take this nested map concept to further levels. You
may have components within a chapter that make sense to group into
a map. This is especially useful if you reuse these components in
other maps or deliverables.</p></body></topic>
