<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "idd357d5ac-96ac-4968-a83f-172ce378aea3" status = "new"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Including FM Files in a Generated Book</title>
<shortdesc status = "new">If needed, you can mix FM binary files
with DITA-sourced files in the generated book.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "UNK"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-28"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "new"><p><indexterm>title page, including</indexterm><indexterm>include
FM files in book</indexterm><indexterm>book, include FM files</indexterm>There
may be times that you’ll want to include FrameMaker binary (<filepath>.fm</filepath>)
files in a book that’s created by the <uicontrol>Generate Book from
Map</uicontrol> command. One particular situation is for the addition
of a title page but there may be other uses as well. For example,
you may have content that you want to include in a book that has
not yet been converted to DITA. With this feature you can build
a book that contains some DITA-sourced chapters as well as some
conventional, unstructured chapters.</p>
<p>DITA-FMx provides an “Include Files” feature that is implemented
through the <filepath conref = "ditafmx_shared.xml#common/bookbuild-ini"></filepath> file.
These files are added to the book at the beginning of the book-build
process, just after the DITA files have been aggregated into FM
files. To include FM files you’ll specify their file name and position
in the book (where a position of “1” is the first file in the book).
You can also optionally define a “mapelemtype” value to be associated
with this file so you can control the pagination properties. To
include a title page in the book as the first file and to define
this as a type of “titlepage,” the following sections should be
added to the <filepath conref = "ditafmx_shared.xml#common/bookbuild-ini"></filepath> file:</p>
<codeblock outputclass = "ini">[IncludeFiles] 
1=title.fm 
 
[IncludeFileTypes] 
1=titlepage</codeblock>
<p><indexterm>IncludeFiles INI section</indexterm><indexterm>IncludeFileTypes
INI section</indexterm>The IncludeFiles section specifies the position
and file name, where the file name is relative to the book file.
You can specify that multiple files are added to the book, just
make sure that the “position” values are always unique, and the
files are ordered from the lowest position to the highest. The IncludeFileTypes
section defines the “mapelemtype” value for the files at each position.
You can use values that match those that are map element types in
DITA (such as “chapter” or “appendix”) and you can create your own
values (such as “titlepage”). Be sure to define the NumberingFirst
and NumberingDefault sections as needed to assign numbering and pagination
values to these mapelemtype values.</p></body></topic>
