<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>

<?Fm Condition DITA-Prolog AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Comment AsIs NO_OVERRIDE hide?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_SYSTEM_HIDEELEMENT AsIs NO_OVERRIDE hide?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_TRACK_CHANGES_ADDED Forest%20Green SINGLE_UNDERLINE hide?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_TRACK_CHANGES_DELETED Red STRIKETHROUGH hide?>

<?Fm BoolCondExpr "" State 0?>


<?Fm TrackChange Off PreviewState PREVIEW_OFF_TRACK_CHANGE?>
<topic id = "id067FF600KHS"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Insert Topicref</title>
<shortdesc>Add a new topicref to a DITA map file or change the selected
topicref to reference a new file.</shortdesc>
<prolog><critdates><created date = "UNK"/>
<revised modified = "2008-02-24"/>
<revised modified = "2008-04-04"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p>New topicref elements can be added with the <uicontrol>Insert
Topicref</uicontrol> command or by inserting a topicref element
from the element catalog. Inserting a topicref displays a file dialog,
letting you select the referenced file. When the file is selected,
a topicref element is inserted at the current insertion point and
an fm-topicreflabel element is inserted as a child of the topicref
element. Topicref elements can reference other DITA topic files
or DITA map files. </p>
<p><indexterm class = "- topic/indexterm ">fm-topicreflabel element</indexterm>The
fm-topicreflabel element only exists within the FrameMaker environment and
provides an object that displays a label that can be double-clicked
to open the associated file. When the file is saved to XML, the
fm-topicref element is removed. When opening a DITA map, topicref
elements are automatically populated with fm-topicref label elements.
When the fm-topicreflabel element is generated on file open, the
label text is extracted from the navtitle attribute of the topicref
element. If the title text of the target topic changes, you can
update the navtitle text (and thus the label) by using the <uicontrol>Update
References</uicontrol> command.</p></body></topic>
