<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="FrameMaker\Structure\xml\DITA"?><?dtall dict="MyCo"?><task
    id = "id524d3bac-215f-4504-8473-76d46bbe39a9"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Cloning the Default Structure Applications</title>
<shortdesc>The first step in customizing the layout or formatting
of a structure application is to create your own application; the
easiest way to create your own is to clone the existing apps.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "UNK"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-24"/></critdates></prolog>
<taskbody><prereq><p status = "changed">First, copy the <filepath
    status = "changed">FrameMaker\Structure\xml\DITA-FMx_1.2</filepath> folder
(with all subfolders included) to a new folder name, for our purposes
here, we’ll call it MyCo-DITA-1.2. In the new MyCo-DITA-1.2 folder
are the three application folders (Topic, Map, and Book), and the
DTD folder. </p><p status = "new">You’ll be modifying files in the
application folders, and leaving the DTD folder as it is (unless
you’re specializing, which we won’t go into here). You’ll want to
make the same initial changes to each of the applications (replace <i
    status = "new">APP</i> with the Topic, Map, or Book application
in the steps below).</p></prereq>
<steps><step><cmd status = "changed">In the new <filepath status = "new">MyCo-DITA-1.2\Topic</filepath> folder
open the <filepath status = "changed">topic_1.2.edd.fm</filepath> file
in FrameMaker. At the top of the file, you’ll see a line that says
“Structured Application: DITA-FMx-Topic-1.2”, change that to “MyCo-DITA-1.2-Topic”.
Save this file, but keep it open for now.</cmd></step>
<step><cmd status = "changed">In the <filepath status = "changed">MyCo-DITA-1.2\Topic</filepath> folder
open the <filepath status = "changed">topic_1.2.template.fm</filepath> file
in FrameMaker. Choose <menucascade><uicontrol>File</uicontrol>
<uicontrol>Import</uicontrol><uicontrol>Element Definitions</uicontrol></menucascade>,
select the <filepath status = "changed">topic_1.2.edd.fm</filepath> EDD
file from the list and choose Import.</cmd></step>
<step><cmd>Save and close the template, then save and close the
EDD.</cmd></step>
<step><cmd status = "changed">In the <filepath status = "changed">MyCo-DITA-1.2\Topic</filepath> folder
open the <filepath status = "changed">structapps-stub_topic_1.2.fm</filepath> file in
FrameMaker. Change all instances of “DITA-FMx” to “MyCo-DITA”.</cmd>
<info status = "changed">This involves modifying the text of a variable.
You’ll actually want to create a new variable and use that, don’t
just modify the content of the existing variable; if you modify
the content of the variable, it may break other applications since this
“stub” file is imported into the structure application definitions
file.<ol><li>Open the Variable dialog (<menucascade><uicontrol>Special</uicontrol>
<uicontrol>Variable</uicontrol></menucascade>).</li>
<li>Select “DITA-FMx-Path” from the list and choose Edit Definition.</li>
<li status = "changed">In the Edit user variable dialog, change
the name from “DITA-FMx-Path” to “MyCo-DITA-Path”, then in the Definition
field change “DITA-FMx” to “MyCo-DITA”. Then choose Add then Done.
Choose Done again in the Variables dialog.</li>
<li status = "changed">Double-click the first DITA-FMx-Path variable
and in the Variables dialog select “MyCo-DITA-Path” and choose Replace.</li>
<li>Now copy and paste this new variable overall instances of it
in the stub file (in the Template, DTD, Read/Write Rules, and numerous
places in Entity Locations).</li></ol></info></step>
<step><cmd>Save and close the stub file.</cmd></step>
<step><cmd status = "changed">Now open the structure application
definitions file with the <menucascade><uicontrol>Structure Tools</uicontrol>
<uicontrol>Edit Application Definitions</uicontrol></menucascade> command.</cmd></step>
<step><cmd>Place the insertion point just after the Version element
(use the Structure View window to see this location easily), and
choose <menucascade><uicontrol>File</uicontrol><uicontrol>Import</uicontrol>
<uicontrol>File</uicontrol></menucascade>. Navigate to the new <filepath
    status = "changed">structapps-stub_topic_1.2.fm</filepath> file
and select it. In the Import Text Flow By Reference dialog, accept
the defaults and choose Import.</cmd></step></steps>
<postreq><p status = "changed">Repeat this task for each of the
applications, Topic, Map, and Book. Once you have updated each application,
you’ll have created a “clone” of the default applications and are
now ready to customize them as needed.</p></postreq></taskbody></task>
