<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "id08C1B0R60Y4"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>MapToBook</title>
<shortdesc>Runs the DITA map to FM book conversion process.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "UNK"/>
<revised modified = "2015-03-31"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p>This function generates an FM book and FM chapter files
from the specified DITA map. It also runs the FixBookRefs and LoadReferences
functions to properly resolve all references. If this function is
used to generate an FM book, you should not use the FixBookRefs
and LoadReferences functions. All parameters listed below are required.</p>
<section id = "id085HGH00RHT" status = "changed"><title>Syntax</title><codeblock status = "changed">F_ApiCallClient("ditafmx", "MapToBook |<varname>mapName</varname> |<varname>appName</varname> |<varname>outBookName</varname>");</codeblock><dl>
<dlentry><dt><varname>mapName</varname></dt>
<dd>Full path and filename of the DITA map to use as the source
for the book. To use the “current” document as the map, use a “.”
(period) as the <varname>mapName</varname> value. Required.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt><varname>appName</varname></dt>
<dd>Name of the structure application to use for the conversion.
Required.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt><varname>outBookName</varname></dt>
<dd>Path and filename of the new book file to generate. If a relative
path is used for the <varname>outBookName</varname>, it is assumed
to be relative to the DITA map being processed. Required.</dd></dlentry></dl><note
conref = "ditafmx_shared.xml#common/fmxapi_auto" status = "changed"></note></section>
<section><title>Return Value</title><dl compact = "yes"><dlentry><dt>0</dt>
<dd>Failure. Unable to update the specified document. It is also
possible that DITA-FMx is not available for calls. Verify that DITA-FMx
is registered in the <filepath>maker.ini</filepath> file using the
client name of “ditafmx”.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>&lt;0</dt>
<dd>Failure. The number of parameters passed (as a negative number).
If more or fewer than 4 parameters are passed, that number will
returned as a negative number.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>>0</dt>
<dd>Successfully converted the specified map (this is the value
of the generated <varname>bookId</varname>).</dd></dlentry></dl></section></body></topic>
