<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="ditaarch:DITAArchVersion"?><topic id = "id1413H0407HT"
    status = "new"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Using Keyspaces in DITA-FMx</title>
<shortdesc status = "new">In DITA-FMx, a keyspace consists of all
keys defined in a root map and all submaps, optionally filtered
by an associated ditaval file.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author status = "changed">Scott Prentice</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "2014-01-03"/>
<revised modified = "2015-03-28"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "new"><p status = "new">The implementation of keyspaces
in <ph keyref = "prodname"/> is a bit different than that in default FM-DITA
(and perhaps other tools as well).</p>
<p status = "new">Each registered key space is stored as a “.keyspace”
file in the user’s DITA-FMx folder (<menucascade status = "new">
<uicontrol status = "new">DITA-FMx</uicontrol>
<uicontrol status = "new">Open DITA-FMx Folder</uicontrol></menucascade>).
The format of this file is XML, and contains all of the necessary
data (normalized and filtered) to insert and display key references
for that key space. This is not a DITA file, so don’t try to open
it using a FrameMaker DITA structured application. If you’re curious,
take a look by opening it in a text editor; the structure will be
apparent.</p>
<p status = "new">When you create a map and start adding key definitions
to it, use the Keyspace Manager to register the root map. Consider
making use of the Keyspace Generation feature (see <xref  keyref
= "keyspace-options" type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local"
status = "new"></xref>) so that the keyspace file is kept in sync
with the key definitions in the map.</p>
<p status = "new">If you are using submaps, remember to register
the root map, not the submap; the key space should always be defined
by the root map. As a convenience feature, DITA-FMx will automatically
update the keyspace, even when working on a submap, if the submap
includes an “fmx-root-map” <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">othermeta</synph> element.
This feature is described in <xref  keyref = "keyspace-options"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local" status = "new"></xref>.</p>
<p status = "new">If you are working with multiple projects and
thus multiple keyspaces, consider using the Keyspace Resolution
feature (also described in <xref  keyref = "keyspace-options" type
= "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local" status = "new"></xref>)
to automatically change the default keyspace when the root map or
an associated submap is opened.</p>
<p status = "new">When registering a keyspace, you have the option
to assign an associated ditaval file. If you are setting up key
definitions that are modified by ditaval filtering, you may want
to select one of the filtering scenarios as the default for editing.
You can always change the ditaval file associated with a keyspace
to switch filtering schemes if needed. If no ditaval is assigned
to a keyspace, all key definitions are included in that keyspace
(duplicate keys are ignored; first key wins).</p>
<p status = "new">Only registered ditaval files are available to
be assigned to a keyspace. Use the Ditaval Manager to register a
ditaval file.</p>
<p status = "new">When publishing through the DITA-FMx Generate
Book from Map command, the ditaval file selected in the Book-Build
Options dialog or specified in the book-build INI file will be applied
to the keyspace regardless of the current default keyspace configuration.</p>
<note type = "important">In order to use keys, you must be using
DITA 1.2 or greater. This is determined by the ditaarch:DITAArchVersion
attribute on the “topic” element. The DITA version is not typically
assigned explicitly, but has a default value that will affect the
availability of these features in DITA-FMx.</note></body></topic>
