<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "idd795412c-bcc4-4716-87bd-d41c9b18ef54" status = "new"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Setting Up PDF Bookmarks</title>
<shortdesc status = "new">It can be tricky to get the PDF bookmarks
set up properly, but it’s worth the effort.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "UNK"/>
<revised modified = "2015-03-31"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "new"><p><indexterm>PDF bookmarks</indexterm><indexterm>bookmarks,
PDF</indexterm>When generating a PDF from a book, the default list
of paragraph styles used to create the bookmarks contains all paragraph
styles that exist in all files in the book, but the include/exclude
settings are defined by those in the first file in the book. If you
want the bookmark list to be ready to use (without needing to move
items over to the exclude list every time), you must make sure that
the first file in the book contains all of the styles in all files,
as well as being set up with the proper include/exclude settings.</p>
<p status = "changed">Use the <uicontrol>Merge Para Tags</uicontrol> command
to copy the paragraph tags from all other templates in a book.</p>
<p>If the first file in the book is generated from a DITA topic,
you’ll need to set up the app’s template file as described below.
If the first file in the book is a generated file, you’ll need to
perform this setup on the generated list template. Or if the first
file is a title page, that file needs to be set up accordingly.</p>
<ol><li><p>Import all paragraph styles from all possible documents
into the file. It’s OK to have more styles than are used, but any
that are in files other than the “first” file will show up in the
“included” bookmark list.</p></li>
<li><p>Open the file and run the <menucascade><uicontrol>Format</uicontrol>
<uicontrol>Document</uicontrol><uicontrol>PDF Setup</uicontrol></menucascade> command.</p></li>
<li><p>In the <wintitle>PDF Setup</wintitle> dialog, on the <uicontrol>Bookmarks</uicontrol> tab,
select <uicontrol>Generate PDF Bookmarks</uicontrol> and “Paragraphs”
as the <uicontrol>Bookmark Source</uicontrol>, then set up the “Include” and
“Don’t Include” styles and adjust the bookmark level as needed.</p></li>
<li><p>Set any other properties as needed in the <wintitle>PDF Setup</wintitle> dialog,
then choose the <uicontrol>Set</uicontrol> button. This saves the
PDF setup data to the file.</p></li></ol>
<note>This process will only work for FM binary files, you cannot
save this setup data to an XML file.</note>
<fig audience = "help web print"><title>PDF Setup dialog box</title><image
href="images/pdfsetup.png" align="left" placement="break"  otherprops
= "fmdpi:110"/></fig>
<note type = "tip">To quickly move all paragraph tags from the left
list to the right list, hold down the SHIFT key and click the ‘->’
(right arrow) button.</note></body></topic>
