<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="dtd"?><?dtall dict="xsl:attribute"?><?dtall dict="xsl:value"?><topic
    id = "id3a2152b0-95cf-4a97-9f6a-2921c293cc2a"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Adding Map to Book Metadata Mappings</title>
<shortdesc>Extending the default metadata mappings allows you to
pass custom element and attribute data from the map to the generated
book and component files.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "UNK"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-29"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p>Two DITA-FMx features read the attribute values on the <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">fm-ditabook</synph> element (the
root of a generated book file). These attributes can define values
that are passed to the book components as FrameMaker variables.
These attributes can also be used to control the show/hide state
of conditions in the generated book components. For information
on enabling these features see the ImportAttrsAsVars, and ImportAttrsAsConds
parameter information in <xref href = "ditafmx_ref_book-buildinifile.xml#id84800a54-1228-438f-881d-08ce097eba90"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref>.</p>
<p>In order to add your own metadata mappings, you need to modify
a number of files in the Book structure application. The following
is an overview of the steps required; details are provided below.</p>
<ol><li status = "changed">Modify the Book EDD to add new attributes
to the <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">fm-ditabook</synph> element
definition, then import the updated EDD into the Book template.</li>
<li status = "changed">Modify the <filepath>fmx-book_1.2.dtd</filepath> file
to add the new attribute definitions.</li>
<li status = "changed">Modify the <filepath>bookmap2fmbook.xsl</filepath> file
to copy the desired metadata (attributes or element content) into
the new <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">fm-ditabook</synph> attributes.</li></ol>
<p>Specific information regarding the modification of the DTD and
XSL files are provided below.</p>
<section><title>Modifying the fmx-book_1.2.dtd file</title><p
    status = "changed">The <filepath>fmx-book_1.2.dtd</filepath> file
is found in the <filepath status = "changed">dtd-fmx</filepath> folder.</p><ol>
<li><p status = "changed">Open the <filepath>fmx-book_1.2.dtd</filepath> file
and locate the attribute definitions for the <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">fm-ditabook</synph> element. The unaltered
attribute definition should look like the following.</p><codeblock outputclass = "xml">&lt;!ATTLIST fm-ditabook 
    href CDATA #IMPLIED 
    format CDATA #IMPLIED 
    title CDATA #IMPLIED 
></codeblock></li>
<li><p>Add the new attributes. The example below adds a new “version”
attribute.</p><codeblock outputclass = "xml">&lt;!ATTLIST fm-ditabook 
    href CDATA #IMPLIED 
    format CDATA #IMPLIED 
    title CDATA #IMPLIED 
    version CDATA #IMPLIED 
></codeblock></li>
<li><p>Save and close the DTD file.</p></li></ol></section>
<section><title>Modifying the bookmap2fmbook.xsl file</title><p>The <filepath>bookmap2fmbook.xsl</filepath> file
is used to aggregate the DITA topics into a book file and component
FM files. It can be used to copy data from the DITA map into attributes
of the fm-ditabook element. Most likely you would copy data from
the bookmeta or topicmeta elements, but any accessible element or
attribute data could be used.</p><p>Open the <filepath>bookmap2fmbook.xsl</filepath> file
in a text editor. The default import XSLT file contains some default
mappings that can be copied and modified to create your own. To
locate this code, scan the XSLT file for the following:</p><codeblock expanse = "page" outputclass = "xml">&lt;xsl:attribute name="created"> 
  &lt;xsl:value-of select="translate(//critdates/created[1]/@date,'&amp;#10;',' ')"/> 
&lt;/xsl:attribute></codeblock><p>Just copy the entire xsl:attribute
block (3 lines), change the @name attribute to the value of the
fm-ditabook attribute you want to create, then change the xsl:value-of/@select
code to grab the value of the attribute or element you want to be
assigned to the new attribute. You’ll see examples of both element
and attribute matching, plus code that locates the first or last
instance of that value (in case there may be multiple).</p><p>You’ll
need to add a similar attribute definition for each type of metadata
that you want to extract from the map. Note that even if you don’t
expect there to be more than one instance of a metadata value, it’s
a good practice to explicitly select the first (or last) value,
just in case there are more than one in a file you’re processing.</p><p>Also
note that these attribute definitions are found in two areas in
the XSLT file, in the map template and the bookmap template. You’ll
want to modify both or either as needed.</p></section></body></topic>
