<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "id0824H0ZL05Z"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Build Map from Outline</title>
<shortdesc>Generates a DITA map and stub files from a simple FrameMaker
document or text file.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-02-04 @ 17:37 (scottp)"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-29"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p><indexterm>build map from outline command</indexterm>This
command builds a DITA map and associated DITA topic files based
on the title text in paragraphs in a FrameMaker document (a binary
FM file, not an XML file) or a text file opened in FrameMaker. The
topic type for each topicref is defined by the paragraph tag name,
and the nesting level is defined by the number of tabs that indent
each paragraph. You can optionally provide an “<ph conref = "ditafmx_shared.xml#common/elem-template"></ph>”
to define the initial structure for each new topic file.</p>
<p>A “map from outline” template file is provided in the <filepath
    status = "changed">Structure\xml\DITA-FMx_1.2</filepath> folder.
This file provides the paragraph tags for the basic topic types,
but you can add your own tags for any specialized topic types that
are needed. Any paragraph tags that start with an underscore are
ignored when creating topicrefs. The new DITA map file is named
based on the FM file’s name and all files are created relative to
the FM file.</p>
<p>The paragraph tag named “_map-title” defines the text that will
be used for the map/@title attribute (the map’s title). The paragraph
tags “topic,” “concept,” “task,” and “reference” are used to define
a topicref of the specified type. To specify an <ph conref = "ditafmx_shared.xml#common/elem-template"></ph>,
include the name of the template after the topic title in angle brackets.
For example, in the following paragraphs the first one is tagged
with the “concept” style and the second is tagged with the “task”
style. When converted into a map, it would create two topics, the
first being a concept that used no element template, and the second
a task that used the element template named “new~task~basic-task.fm”.</p>
<codeblock>Linear Objects 
Drawing Lines &lt;basic-task></codeblock>
<p>The file names of the generated topic files are defined by the
New File Name Format in the DITA-FMx Options dialog. This may mean
that the filenames are title-based or they could be based on the
topic’s unique ID, the date/time, or other values. You can also
use that format to create the new files in topic-based folders.</p>
<p>If the text of the paragraph is a DITA file name (must end with
“.xml”, “.dita”, or “.ditamap” and have no spaces), that file name
will be used for the href attribute value. If the paragraph tag
is named “Body” it will assume the “topic” type. This allows you
to open a text file that is a listing of files, and quickly generate
a DITA map from that list.</p></body></topic>
