<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [
]>
<?dtall dict="attr"?><?dtall dict="desc"?><?dtall dict="easyDITA"?><?dtall
dict="fn"?><?dtall dict="hrefs"?><?dtall dict="msgblock"?><?dtall dict="relinks"?><?dtall
dict="SaveAs"?><?dtall dict="SubjectScheme"?><?dtall dict="syntaxdiagram"?><?dtall
dict="TextLine"?><?dtall dict="toolbar"?><?dtall dict="uninstalled"?><topic
    id = "id067FFA00K4Y"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Limitations</title>
<shortdesc>Known limitations in the current version of DITA-FMx.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>test</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-10-13"/>
<revised modified = "2017-11-20"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p id = "id_066EJI0F05Z">The following list describes the
currently known issues that apply to using DITA-FMx on all supported
versions of FrameMaker (see below for version-specific issues):</p>
<ul id = "id_066GG700J5Z"><li><p>DITA 1.3 is not currently supported
by DITA-FMx. We are assessing which features to support; if you
have specific needs, please contact us.</p><p>While no support is
provided out of the box, there is no reason that DITA-FMx would
not support the DITA 1.3 model if an appropriately defined structure application
were developed. The aspects of DITA 1.3 that will not currently work,
involve new methods for ditaval filtering, scoped key resolution,
and cross-deliverable linking.</p></li>
<li><p>The following DITA 1.2 features are not currently supported:</p><ul>
<li><p>keyrefs to topicref-based elements are not supported</p></li>
<li><p>key element references to <synph outputclass = "element">fm-indexterm</synph>, <synph
    outputclass = "element">indexterm</synph>, and <synph
    outputclass = "element">indextermref</synph> are not supported</p></li>
<li><p>key element references will provide the defined content but
will not currently provide a hyperlink to a provided <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">href</synph> target</p></li>
<li status = "new"><p>inline elements within key element references
are unwrapped; the content will remain, but the markup is deleted</p></li>
<li><p>text from conrefs and keyrefs within a map will not be passed
to the book-build process</p></li>
<li><p><indexterm>conaction attribute, support</indexterm>the <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">conaction</synph> attribute is not
supported</p></li>
<li><p><indexterm>Learning and Training model, support</indexterm>a
“Learning” structure application (based on the Learning and Training specialization)
is provided for testing purposes only and is not considered to be
production-ready; an update will be provided in a future release</p></li>
<li><p><indexterm>SubjectScheme model, support</indexterm>a “SubjectScheme”
structure application is not currently provided</p></li></ul></li>
<li><p>When generating an FM book from a map, you may get the following
messages in the FrameMaker Log file:</p><ul><li><p>XML Parser Message: <b>“ID
'<i>TOPICID</i>' has already been used”</b></p><p>This message is
caused when your topic files contain duplicate IDs. This can happen
when you clone a topic file to create a new topic file or if you
include the same topic in multiple places in the map. Both of these
situations are valid as far as DITA is concerned, but FrameMaker
doesn’t like to see duplicate IDs in a single book. This is just
a warning and can generally be ignored.</p><p>The only situation
where this duplicate ID issue will cause problems or possibly unexpected
results, is when you have xrefs or related links to a topic where
the ID exists in multiple places in a given chapter file. The reference
will always end up pointing at the first instance of the ID in a generated
FM chapter file.</p></li></ul></li>
<li><p>For the <uicontrol>Apply Ditaval</uicontrol> command, only
the <synph outputclass = "element">prop</synph> ditaval element
is supported. Other elements may be recognized in a future release
if that is seen as beneficial.</p><p>The <i>as conditions</i> option
of the <uicontrol>Apply Ditaval</uicontrol> command does not necessarily result
in filtering that matches that of the DITA Open Toolkit. The conditions
are applied properly based on the filtering attribute values, but
the default hide/show logic of FrameMaker conditions is not the
same as that used by the OT. When using the <i>as conditions</i> option,
it is best to use ditaval files that only use the “exclude” action
attribute; this will provide more reliable results. Due to the nature
of conditional tagging, this option cannot remove components from a
book. If this is needed, use the <i>by deletion</i> option.</p><p>The <i>by
deletion</i> option of the <uicontrol>Apply Ditaval</uicontrol> command,
more closely emulates the filtering done by the DITA-OT. However,
the <i>by deletion</i> option only supports the “include” and “exclude”
action attributes; the “flag” action is not supported (if “flag”
is needed, use the <i>as conditions</i> option).</p></li>
<li><p>Because a graphic object in FrameMaker cannot have children,
the <synph outputclass = "element">alt</synph> and <synph
    outputclass = "element">longdescref</synph> elements are not
fully supported. The text of the <synph outputclass = "element">alt</synph> element will
round-trip and can be edited through the Object Properties (Object
Attributes) dialog, but any attributes on the <synph
    outputclass = "element">alt</synph> element will be discarded
on file open. The <synph outputclass = "element">longdescref</synph> element
will be discarded on file open.</p></li>
<li><p>When using TextLine graphic overlay objects, do not use a
Center or Right alignment, only use the default Left alignment.
Using an alignment of Center or Right will result in the text line
position shifting to the left or right when the file is reopened.
This will be fixed in a future release.</p></li>
<li><p>In a relationship table, only <synph outputclass = "attribute">href</synph> references
to files are honored. Any <synph outputclass = "attribute">href</synph> attributes
that include references to topic IDs will be stripped down to just
the file name for processing and creation of related links. This
may change in a future update.</p></li>
<li status = "new"><p><indexterm>footnotes, referencing</indexterm><indexterm>fn
element</indexterm>DITA-FMx does not support the “use by reference”
feature of DITA footnotes. This is where the footnote reference
number only shows up at the referenced (via <synph
    outputclass = "element">xref</synph>) location but not at the
location of the <synph outputclass = "element">fn</synph> element.
In all cases, there will be a reference number generated by the <synph
    outputclass = "element">fn</synph> element. You may add references
to that footnote with a formatted reference (<synph
    outputclass = "element">fm-xref</synph>).</p></li>
<li><p><indexterm>indexterm</indexterm>Indexterms with multiple
child elements that are siblings, will not round-trip properly.
On import, the sibling <synph outputclass = "element">indexterm</synph>s
are incorrectly converted into FM index syntax, which means the
exported <synph outputclass = "element">indexterm</synph>s will
be nested rather than siblings. A workaround is to disable <synph
    outputclass = "element">indexterm</synph> conversion on import and
export (although this will not allow you to generate a FM index).
This may be fixed in a future update.</p></li>
<li><p>Xrefs within the link/desc element will not resolve properly
on file open. After file open, running the Update References command
will resolve these references. This may be fixed in a future update.</p></li>
<li><p>Backslashes used in an external <synph outputclass = "element">xref</synph> (either
in the element text or in the <synph outputclass = "attribute">href</synph> value)
will not render as expected. You should use forward slashes if at all
possible. This is due to a FrameMaker limitation and cannot be resolved.</p></li>
<li><p>The <uicontrol>Generate Book From Map</uicontrol> command
disallows the building of a book from a DITA map that references
files on multiple disk drives. This appears to be a core FrameMaker
limitation (but this probably isn’t a good idea anyway).</p><p>When
generating a book from a map, any attributes on topicref-based elements that
reference a submap are lost during the XSLT import process. The
“merge” process replaces the <i>referencing</i> topicref with the <i>referenced</i> topicref
(the root topicref in the referenced map). Therefore, any filtering
(or other) attributes intended to affect the generated book, should
be placed on the <i>referenced</i> topicref rather than the <i>referencing</i> topicref.</p></li>
<li><p>If an XML file is “pretty-printed” and a line breaks after
an inline element (such as a <synph outputclass = "element">ph</synph>),
when opened in Frame the space between that element and the following
word will be lost.</p></li>
<li><p>Child elements within an <synph outputclass = "element">xref</synph> or <synph
    outputclass = "element">link</synph> are lost on import if the
Auto-Load Xrefs option is enabled. If your xrefs contain child elements,
disable this option.</p></li>
<li><p>Conrefs within titles won’t be included when you run the
Update References command in a DITA map unless the target file is
already open. If you have conrefs in your titles, you should open
the file first before running the Update References command.</p></li>
<li><p>Deleting an <synph outputclass = "element">fm-reflabel</synph> element
from a DITA map file without deleting the entire <synph
    outputclass = "element">topicref</synph>, may result in the
leading symbol being left in the map. This is a temporary issue
and will go away the next time you open the file; it has no effect
on the ability to process the files.</p></li>
<li><p>The <synph outputclass = "element">syntaxdiagram</synph> child
elements should round-trip properly, but the formatting of these
elements may not be optimal. We will focus on providing better support
for these elements in DITA-FMx 2.x.</p></li></ul>
<p otherprops = "fm140" status = "new"><b>Issues that relate to
using DITA-FMx with FrameMaker 2017:</b></p>
<ul><li><p>FM version 14.0.2 or later is required for use with DITA-FMx
due to FDK library updates with that update.</p></li>
<li status = "new"><p><indexterm>FM 2017, welcome screen</indexterm>The
FM 2017 “welcome screen” has no API, so the DITA-related links and buttons
will not work when DITA-FMx is installed. When Adobe provides an
API to these items, we’ll hook it up.</p></li></ul>
<p otherprops = "fmxmla"><b>Issues that relate to using DITA-FMx
with FrameMaker XML Author (FM 12 and 2015):</b></p>
<ul><li><p><indexterm>XML Author</indexterm><indexterm>FMXA</indexterm><indexterm>FrameMaker
XML Author</indexterm>DITA-FMx does not work well with FrameMaker
XML Author. Many commands work fine, but due to the inability to
open FM binary files, you cannot create new DITA files through the
DITA-FMx interface and the publishing features will also not work.
You can work around this limitation by opening an existing XML file and
saving it to a new name (remember to recreate the topic ID). You
can also use DITA-FMx to author files that are stored in a CMS such
as XDocs or easyDITA.</p></li></ul>
<p otherprops = "fm110"><b>Issues that relate to using DITA-FMx
with FrameMaker 11:</b></p>
<ul><li><p>Due to changes in the FrameMaker 11 API, the “Open Maps
in Document View” option does not work on the initial open of a
map. It will however, work when opening a supmap from a topicref
in a map. If a solution is found it will be provided in a future
update.</p></li>
<li><p><indexterm>code view problems (FM11)</indexterm>Be aware
that using the FrameMaker 11 Code View can strip leading spaces from
preformatted elements (i.e., <synph outputclass = "element">codeblock</synph>, <synph
    outputclass = "element">lines</synph>, <synph
    outputclass = "element">msgblock</synph>, <synph
    outputclass = "element">pre</synph>). This is a core FM bug,
that will hopefully be fixed soon. Unfortunately, there’s nothing
that DITA-FMx can do about this (other than to warn you about it).</p></li></ul>
<p otherprops = "fm100"><b>Issues that relate to using DITA-FMx
with FrameMaker 10:</b></p>
<ul><li><p><indexterm>ditamap, save as</indexterm><indexterm>Save
Ditamap As</indexterm><indexterm>composite documents, support</indexterm><indexterm>book
with FM compo nents, support</indexterm><indexterm>PDF export, support</indexterm>FrameMaker
10 includes a number of “Save Ditamap As” options that are not functional
when DITA-FMx is installed (because the FM10 DITA support is uninstalled).
The following SaveAs options are not supported:</p><ul><li>Composite
Document</li>
<li>Book with FM Components</li>
<li>PDF</li></ul></li>
<li><p>The two left-most buttons on the Resource Manager (map editor)
toolbar are non-functional when DITA-FMx is installed. We are looking
into options for enabling them, but for now you must use the element
catalog to insert topic referencing elements (<synph
    outputclass = "element">topicref</synph>, <synph
    outputclass = "element">chapter</synph>, <synph
    outputclass = "element">appendix</synph>, etc.). The remainder
of the buttons seem to work properly with DITA-FMx.</p></li></ul>
<p otherprops = "fm90"><b>Issues that relate to using DITA-FMx with
FrameMaker 9:</b></p>
<ul><li><p><indexterm>ditamap, save as</indexterm><indexterm>Save
Ditamap As</indexterm><indexterm>composite documents, support</indexterm><indexterm>book
with FM components, support</indexterm><indexterm>PDF export, support</indexterm>FrameMaker
9 includes a number of “Save Ditamap As” options that are not functional
when DITA-FMx is installed (because the FM9 DITA support is uninstalled).
The following SaveAs options are not supported:</p><ul><li>Composite
Document</li>
<li>Book with FM Components</li>
<li>PDF</li></ul></li>
<li><p>The four left-most buttons on the Resource Manager (map editor)
toolbar are non-functional when DITA-FMx is installed. We are looking
into options for enabling them, but for now you must use the element
catalog to insert topic referencing elements (<synph
    outputclass = "element">topicref</synph>, <synph
    outputclass = "element">chapter</synph>, <synph
    outputclass = "element">appendix</synph>, etc.).</p></li></ul>
<p otherprops = "fm80"><b>Issues that relate to using DITA-FMx with
FrameMaker 8:</b></p>
<ul><li><p>A bug exists in FrameMaker 8 (and FM7.2) that causes
it to crash if more than approximately 350 XML files are opened
in the same session. In normal authoring use this limitation does
not cause any problems, but if you are publishing a book that contains
more than 300 topics, it is very likely that you’ll run into this
problem. The only workaround is to convert your maps into a book in
multiple segments and assemble the final book once all of the components have
been built (restarting FrameMaker in between each build). DITA-FMx displays
a warning after opening more than 300 files to remind you to restart FrameMaker.
This bug has been fixed in FrameMaker 9.</p></li></ul>
<p otherprops = "fm72"><b>Issues that relate to using DITA-FMx with
FrameMaker 7.2:</b></p>
<ul><li><p>In the FM7.2 version of DITA-FMx, double-byte characters
are garbled in the fm-topicreflabel elements, and don’t update properly.</p></li></ul>
<p>Using DITA-FMx for DITA authoring in binary FrameMaker files
is not recommended. Many of the features of DITA-FMx rely on the
files being XML (allowing them to be parsed on disk). The following
are reported issues, but there may be others:</p>
<ul><li><p>A file that can’t be opened due to missing fonts or images
and it is the target of a conref or <synph outputclass = "element">xref</synph>,
the Reference Manager won’t display when the conref or <synph
    outputclass = "element">xref</synph> is double-clicked. This
can be resolved by opening the referenced file before double-clicking
the conref or xref.</p></li>
<li><p>Double-clicking a conref then choosing Update, will delete
the conref.</p></li></ul>
<p>Please send any problems or suggestions to &lt;<ph audience = "web">ditafmx-help
AT leximation DOT com</ph><xref href = "mailto:ditafmx-help@leximation.com"
format = "html" scope = "external" audience = "help">ditafmx-help@leximation.com</xref>>.</p></body></topic>
