<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="FrameMaker\DITA"?><topic
    id = "id46037b3b-abad-4302-acca-9b86261a381f" status = "changed"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Upgrading from DITA-FMx 1.0 or 1.1</title>
<shortdesc status = "changed">Tips for a painless migration from
an earlier version of DITA-FMx.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>test</author>
<critdates><created date = "2009-02-19"/>
<revised modified = "2014-04-13"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "changed"><p status = "changed">DITA-FMx 2.0 should
handle your existing DITA-FMx 1.1 structure applications without
any problems, especially if you’re upgrading from the latest release (1.1.18).
If you are using an older app, some of the new features that rely
on specific structure application settings may not work. But you
should be able to install the update and continue working, and expect
the same level of functionality that you’re used to. When you are
ready to migrate the new features into your structure application,
you should review the <xref href = "ditafmx_apprequirements.xml#id0833I0F01HS"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref> topic.</p>
<p status = "new">The default structure application provided with
DITA-FMx 2.0 supports the DITA 1.2 model. You should be able to
use this app for DITA files created with earlier DITA models, but
you can also continue to use your existing apps if you prefer.</p>
<note type = "tip" status = "changed">The changes made to the structure
applications are documented in the “Structure Application Updates”
sections of the <xref href = "ditafmx_revisions.xml#id07C590FA05Z"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local" status = "new"></xref> for
each update. It may be useful to review all of these changes from
your version when upgrading a custom structure application.</note>
<p status = "new">Because DITA-FMx 2.0 installs into a new directory
structure (<filepath status = "new">FrameMaker\DITA-FMx-2</filepath>),
it will not overwrite your DITA-FMx installation. After running
the installer, run FrameMaker and you’ll be prompted to install
the new DITA 1.2 structure applications. These are also installed
to a new directory structure so will not overwrite your existing
application files.</p>
<p status = "new">This allows you to maintain both DITA-FMx 1.1
and 2.0 installations side-by-side. To switch from one to the other,
see <xref href = "ditafmx_installing_fmx11and20.xml#id1413F0N035Z"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local" status = "new"></xref>.</p>
<p status = "new">After installing DITA-FMx 2.0, you may want to
migrate some of the settings in the 1.1 <filepath status = "new">ditafmx.ini</filepath> file.
There have been some changes to this INI file, but some of the settings
will be the same.</p></body></topic>
