<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="darkblue"?><?dtall dict="ForceTablesWide"?><?dtall dict="min"?><?dtall
dict="PreserveTableWidths"?><?dtall dict="pgwide"?><?dtall dict="stentry"?><?dtall
dict="tableformat"?><?dtall dict="tbody"?><?dtall dict="thead"?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Data Forest%20Green NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Cleanup Green NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-StatusNew AsIs CHANGEBAR show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-StatusChanged AsIs CHANGEBAR show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-StatusUnchanged AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Comment AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Prolog AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_TRACK_CHANGES_ADDED Forest%20Green SINGLE_UNDERLINE hide?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_TRACK_CHANGES_DELETED Red STRIKETHROUGH hide?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_SYSTEM_HIDEELEMENT AsIs NO_OVERRIDE hide?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-StatusDeleted AsIs STRIKETHROUGH show?>

<?Fm BoolCondExpr "DITA-Data"OR"DITA-Cleanup"OR"DITA-Comment"OR"DITA-Prolog"OR"DITA-StatusNew"OR"DITA-StatusChanged"OR"DITA-StatusUnchanged"OR"DITA-StatusDeleted" State 0?>


<?Fm TrackChange Off PreviewState PREVIEW_OFF_TRACK_CHANGE?>
<topic id = "id1429F0G0OHS"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Custom Ruling and Shading</title>
<shortdesc status = "changed">Applying ruling and shading to specific
table rows and cells requires additional forethought and setup.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates status = "changed"><created date = "2009-02-08"/>
<revised modified = "2016-09-13"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "changed"><p status = "new">DITA-FMx allows you to
apply custom ruling and shading to table rows or cells based on
the <synph outputclass = "attribute">outputclass</synph> attribute.
Because there is no option to control this formatting through EDD
context rules, you must set up a representative table on an “fmx-tableformat”
reference page in the structure application templates. A sample
page has been added in the default DITA-FMx Topic and Book templates.</p>
<p status = "new">To enable this feature, you must enable the Apply
Custom Ruling and Shading option in the Authoring Options dialog.</p>
<p status = "new">On this reference page (must be created if it
doesn’t exist), create a text frame and add a structure flow that
contains the table types for which you want to provide formatting.
Use the <menucascade status = "new"><uicontrol status = "new">Table</uicontrol>
<uicontrol status = "new">Row Format</uicontrol></menucascade> or <menucascade
    status = "new"><uicontrol status = "new">Table</uicontrol>
<uicontrol status = "new">Custom Ruling and Shading</uicontrol></menucascade> commands
to assign the desired formatting to a row or cell. Then set the outputclass
attribute of that formatted row or cell to the value you want to
use to identify that formatting. Save the template. Be sure to make
similar modifications to both the Topic and Book templates.</p>
<p status = "new">After setting up the template, apply the appropriate
name to the <synph outputclass = "attribute">outputclass</synph> attribute
of row or cell elements in your DITA topic files. When you save
the file, the formatting is transferred from the object on the reference
page to the corresponding object in the topic.</p>
<p status = "new">Keep in mind that the formatting is only applied
to matching row or cell elements. Don’t set the <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">outputclass</synph> on other table
objects (<synph outputclass = "element">thead</synph>, <synph
    outputclass = "element">tbody</synph>, etc.). For example the
formatting of an <synph outputclass = "element">entry</synph> element
on the reference page with an <synph outputclass = "attribute">outputclass</synph> of
“darkblue” will not be applied to an <synph outputclass = "element">stentry</synph> element
with an <synph outputclass = "attribute">outputclass</synph> of
“darkblue,” only to another <synph outputclass = "element">entry</synph> element.</p>
<p status = "new">Also, note that these properties are only applied
by row or cell. The properties applied by row are: row min/max height,
row start position, and row keep w/ next/previous. The properties
applied by cell are ruling and shading (coloring). In order to apply
both row and cell properties, you must define both types of schemes in
your reference page table. Developing very complex ruling, shading,
etc. layouts can be very difficult, so start with a simple case
and slowly add more properties until you understand how this is
done.</p></body></topic>
