<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [
]>
<?dtall dict="ditafmx_app"?><?dtall dict="ditafm_app"?><topic
    id = "id078AAC00PY4"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>DITA Structure Applications</title>
<shortdesc status = "changed">You can use the DITA structure applications
provided with DITA-FMx, those provided by Adobe, or your own custom
applications. If you’re using apps other than the DITA-FMx apps,
you’ll need to make some minor adjustments.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>test</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "UNK"/>
<revised modified = "2017-10-10"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "changed"><p status = "changed">In order for FrameMaker
to properly open and save DITA files, you must have structure applications
that support the authoring of topic and map files. DITA-FMx provides
both of these applications as well as a structure application for
book processing.</p>
<p status = "new">Using the default DITA-FMx structure applications
is the easiest way to get started, because those applications will
support all of the advanced features provided by DITA-FMx.</p>
<note status = "new">If you’re installing on a system where the
user does not have “admin” permissions, you’ll want to install the
structure applications in a more accessible location. For details,
see <xref href = "ditafmx_apprelocation.xml#id3e0f22a6-bded-404b-9a77-2a80461af2bd"
type = "concept" format = "dita" scope = "local" status = "new"></xref>.</note>
<note type = "important" status = "changed">The structure applications
provided with DITA-FMx 2.0 are in FM8 format. This works fine for
FM8 and later, but if you’re using FM7.2, you’ll need to open them
in FM8 and downsave to FM7 format. If you’re unable to do this,
contact Leximation.</note>
<p status = "changed">If you are already working with DITA structure
applications, and want to continue using them, you’ll need to do
the following:</p>
<ul status = "new"><li><p status = "new">Edit the structure application
definition for each of your structure applications. Change the <b
    status = "new">Use API Client</b> node so it references the
client <b status = "new">ditafmx_app</b> instead of <b status = "new">ditafm_app</b>.
This is required; if you do not do this, you’ll get an error message.</p></li>
<li status = "new"><p status = "new">Add new element definitions
that support special features provided by DITA-FMx. For details
see <xref href = "ditafmx_apprequirements.xml#id0833I0F01HS" type
= "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local" status = "new"></xref>.
This is optional, but may limit the available functionality.</p></li>
<li status = "new"><p status = "new">Create a special “Book” application
for publishing. DITA-FMx relies on a structure application for Book
publishing. It is possible that your current “Topic” application
will do the job.</p></li></ul>
<p status = "new">If you want to customize the appearance of default
DITA-FMx structure applications, you should clone the provided structure
application folders and modify the cloned versions. For additional
information, refer to <xref href = "ditafmx_cloningtapps.xml#id524d3bac-215f-4504-8473-76d46bbe39a9"
type = "task" format = "dita" scope = "local" status = "new"></xref>.</p>
<p status = "changed">After installing DITA-FMx, when you run FrameMaker
you should see a message asking to install the default structure
applications. Unless you’re doing something special, you should
choose Yes to this message. To manually install the structure applications
or if you’d like to understand what this automated process is doing,
read the topic titled <xref href = "ditafmx_installing_apps_manual.xml#id078AAC00PY42"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref>.</p>
<note type = "important" status = "new">On <ph conref="ditafmx_shared.xml#common/winvers_new"></ph>,
the automated structure application installation process may fail
unless FrameMaker is run “As Administrator.” Exit FrameMaker, then
right-click the program icon and choose “Run As Administrator.”</note>
<p status = "changed">After the structure applications have been
installed, you may want to take a look at the structure application
definitions so you will better understand how they work. Just choose <menucascade>
<uicontrol>Structure Tools</uicontrol><uicontrol>Edit Application
Definitions</uicontrol></menucascade> to open the structure application
definitions file. You should see the three DITA-FMx structure application definitions
at the top of the file. These are added as text insets to make it
easier to manage. If you need to modify these entries, you’ll ned
to open the source file by double-clicking the inset and choosing
the Open button. When you’re done reviewing the structure application
definitions file, just close the file. You’ll be prompted to save
when closing. Unless you’ve made intentional changes, there is no
need to save.</p></body></topic>
