<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<task id = "id0846D0U015Z"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Setting Up Filtering Groups</title>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-04-06"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-30"/></critdates></prolog>
<taskbody><prereq><p><indexterm>filtering groups</indexterm><indexterm>filtergroups.ini
file</indexterm>Before you can make use of filtering groups, your
EDD must be set up to use the “Strings” attribute type for the attributes
that you want to use with a filtering group. You can optionally
add “default” values to the attribute definitions in the EDD, but that
is not required (and may not be desirable). At a minimum, just change
the “String” type to “Strings” and you should be all set.</p><p
    status = "changed">The default DITA-FMx Topic and Map templates
use the Strings type for all instances of the platform, product,
audience, and otherprops attributes.</p></prereq>
<context><p>The following task creates two filtering groups named
“ProductA” and “ProductB” and sets up unique values for each group
that are available to apply to the attributes specified. Feel free
to change the names and file paths to match those on your system.</p></context>
<steps><step><cmd status = "changed">Using a text editor such as
Notepad, create a file named <filepath>filtergroups.ini</filepath> in
the user’s DITA-FMx folder (<menucascade status = "new">
<uicontrol status = "new">DITA-FMx</uicontrol>
<uicontrol status = "new">Open DITA-FMx Folder</uicontrol></menucascade>).</cmd></step>
<step><cmd>Create a “General” section that defines the group names
and the associated root paths, then create a section for each group
that defines the attribute names and available values.</cmd>
<stepxmp><codeblock>[General] 
ProductA=C:\projects\product-a 
ProductB=C:\projects\product-b 
 
[ProductA] 
product=ProdALite|ProdAFull|ProdASimple 
audience=Novice|Expert|Admin 
platform=Windows|Mac|Linux 
otherprops=001|002|003|004|005|006 
 
[ProductB] 
product=ProdBLite|ProdBFull 
audience=User|Developer|Admin 
platform=Windows|Mac|Linux|Solaris</codeblock></stepxmp></step>
<step><cmd>Save this file.</cmd></step></steps>
<postreq><p>In FrameMaker, when you open a file in Product A (somewhere
below the path <filepath>C:\projects\product-a</filepath>), when
you run the Set Attributes command, and select one of the filtering
attributes from the list, you will be able to select one or more
of the values specified in the INI file.</p></postreq></taskbody></task>
