<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="ix"?><?dtall dict="seealso"?><topic
    id = "idf15ab8fa-7832-45e3-b892-442771c31826"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Index Options</title>
<shortdesc>Allows customization of the import/export processing
of the marker syntax with index-see and index-see-also elements.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "UNK"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-31"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p status = "changed"><indexterm status = "new">index-see
element rendering</indexterm><indexterm status = "new">index-see-also
element rendering</indexterm>Although there are standards for the
formatting of “see” and “see-also” index entries, each organization
may want these entries to be constructed slightly differently. The <uicontrol
    status = "new">Index Options</uicontrol> dialog allows for this
personalization. DITA provides the <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">index-see</synph> and <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">index-see-also</synph> elements for
identifying these type of index entries, but in FrameMaker, the
index syntax is all contained within a single Index marker (in DITA-FMx
this becomes an <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">fm-indexterm</synph> element).
This dialog defines how the DITA elements map to and are converted
from DITA into FrameMaker (and back).</p>
<fig audience = "web"><title>DITA-FMx Index Options dialog box</title><image
href="images/indexoptions.png" align="left" placement="break"  otherprops
= "fmdpi:110"/></fig>
<p>The Index Options dialog provides two main sections, one for
each of the “see” and “see-also” entry types. Within each section
are fields (described below) and a “Resulting Marker Text” area
that dynamically shows the index marker syntax to be generated using
the fields as entered. The textual content used for the sample entries
can be modified in the Sample Entry Values field. Any time a value
requires leading or trailing spaces, wrap it in square or curly
brackets ( “[ .. ]” or “{ .. }” ).</p>
<dl><dlhead><dthd>index-see Options</dthd></dlhead>
<dlentry><dt>Main Terminator</dt>
<dd>Separates the text of the main entry with that of the referenced
entry. Typically a period followed by a space.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Char Tag</dt>
<dd>The name of the character style used to format the “see” reference
entry. This is required even if there is no additional formatting
to be applied because it is the only way for FrameMaker to know
if the index entry is a “see” entry. The character tag “ix-see”
is defined in the default DITA-FMx templates; you are free to modify
the formatting of that tag. If you want to use a different character
tag, you must add that style to the template.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Label</dt>
<dd>The label that separates the main entry and the referenced entry
text. This value will be formatted with the character style specified
in the Char Tag field.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Nesting Separator</dt>
<dd>Separates multiple referenced entries. Typically a comma with
a trailing space.</dd></dlentry></dl>
<dl><dlhead><dthd>index-see-also Options</dthd></dlhead>
<dlentry><dt>Char Tag</dt>
<dd>The name of the character style used to format the “see-also”
reference entry. This is required even if there is no additional
formatting to be applied because it is the only way for FrameMaker
to know if the index entry is a “see-also” entry. The character
tag “ix-seealso” is defined in the default DITA-FMx templates; you
are free to modify the formatting of that tag. If you want to use a
different character tag, you must add that style to the template.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Label</dt>
<dd>The label that separates the main entry and the referenced entry
text. This value will be formatted with the character style specified
in the Char Tag field.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Nesting Separator</dt>
<dd>Separates multiple referenced entries. Typically a comma with
a trailing space.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Forced Sort Value</dt>
<dd>If you want the entry to sort in a particular manner, enter
the forced sort text here.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Entry Separator</dt>
<dd>String that separates multiple top-level target entries. Typically
a semicolon with a trailing space. This value is not represented
in the sample Resulting Marker Text field.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Wrap See-Also Reference</dt>
<dd>If enabled, wraps the entire see-also reference in parenthesis.</dd></dlentry></dl></body></topic>
