<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "id081TB060Y5Z"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Switching Between DITA-FMx and FM8/9/10/11/12/2015-DITA</title>
<shortdesc status = "changed">If needed, you can easily switch between
DITA-FMx and the built-in FM8/9/10/11/12/2015 DITA support.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-02-24"/>
<revised modified = "2015-08-10"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p>For testing purposes, you may want to alternate between
DITA-FMx and the built-in FrameMaker DITA support. Fundamentally,
this is very simple to do, and if you do this frequently, there
are things you can do to make it even easier.</p>
<p>All that is required to switch between these two DITA plugins
is to update the <filepath>maker.ini</filepath> file. When you installed
DITA-FMx, you should have commented out the lines that initialize
the default DITA support. To enable the default support and disable
DITA-FMx, just uncomment the “ditafm” lines and comment out the “ditafmx”
lines. Then to switch back to DITA-FMx just do the reverse. Of course, each
time you modify the <filepath>maker.ini</filepath> file you’ll ned
to restart FrameMaker to initialize the alternate plugin.</p>
<note type = "important">Before modifying the <filepath>maker.ini</filepath> file
you should make a backup and keep it in a safe place.</note>
<p>You may want to set up the <filepath>maker.ini</filepath> file
so it’s easy to make this change. Just move the lines to the end
of the APIClients section and add some comments to look like this
(note that the FM8 DITA lines have been modified slightly):</p>
<codeblock expanse = "page" outputclass = "ini">; Default FM8-DITA 
;ditafm=Standard, FM8-DITA, fminit\ditafm.dll, structured 
;ditafm_app=Standard, FM8-DITA, fminit\ditafm_app.dll, structured 
;ditabook=Standard, FM8-DITA, fminit\ditabook.dll, structured 
;ditaOpenToolkit=Standard, FM8-DITAOT, fminit\openToolkit.dll, structured 
 
; DITA-FMx 
ditafmx=Standard, ditafmx, DITA-FMx\ditafmx_80.dll, structured 
ditafmx_app=Standard, ditafmx_app, DITA-FMx\ditafmx_80_app.dll, structured</codeblock>
<p>This way you can easily add or remove the semicolon to comment
or uncomment the appropriate lines.</p>
<p>One additional step that will streamline this process is to change
the FM8 DITA entry for “ditafm_app” to “ditafmx_app,” then make
the same change in the structure application definitions file (change
“ditafm_app” to “ditafmx_app” in the UseApiClient entries). This
won’t change the functionality of the FM DITA import/export client,
it just means that you can use the same structure application for
both plugins and you won’t have to edit the structapps file each
time you switch. If you call them both “ditafmx_app,” then when
you install an update of DITA-FMx, it will be an easier installation.</p>
<p>Leximation provides a plugin called IniSwitcher that modifies
specified lines in an INI file from a command within FrameMaker.
This plugin was specifically developed to make it easy to switch
between the DITA authoring plugins. If you are interested in using
this plugin, check <xref href = "http://leximation.com/tools" format
= "html" scope = "external">www.leximation.com/tools</xref> or contact
Leximation for more information.</p></body></topic>
