<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "id68d147e8-2097-4621-a411-7a04cc60da2b" status = "new"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Using Templates to Define Alternate TOC Entries</title>
<shortdesc status = "new">It is possible to support multiple styles
of TOC entries for different templates.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "UNK"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-28"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "new"><p status = "changed">By default, the paragraph
styles applied to all titles in all generated FM files are the same
(title.0, title.1, etc., as defined by the Book structure application).
When pulled into a TOC file, they become “title.0TOC”, “title.1TOC”,
and so on. Your TOC generated list template (“<filepath>gentpl~toc.fm</filepath>”)
defines the handing for these styles on the “TOC” reference page.
If you want to be able to support multiple types of entries, such
as “Chapter”, “Appendix”, and “Part”, you’ll need to do the following.</p>
<dl><dlentry><dt>Create a custom EDD and template for each TOC type</dt>
<dd><p>The component template (<filepath status = "changed">tpl~&lt;mapelemtype>.fm</filepath>)
will apply alternate formatting to the specific book component,
but if you want the underlying paragraph styles to change, you need
to create a modified EDD that applies the alternate style, and update
the template to support that style. The actual style may look the
same, but the name needs to be different so it can be handled separately
in the TOC template. </p><p status = "new">For example, if you want
to add support for the appendix element and have your TOC include
both Chapter and Appendix labels, you could do the following:</p><ol>
<li>Copy the default Book EDD (<filepath status = "changed">book_1.2.edd.fm</filepath>)
to a new name, perhaps <filepath status = "changed">book_1.2_appendix.edd.fm</filepath>.</li>
<li>Copy the default Book template (<filepath status = "changed">book_1.2.template.fm</filepath>)
to a new name, perhaps <filepath status = "changed">book_1.2_appendix.template.fm</filepath>.</li>
<li>Edit the <filepath status = "changed">book_1.2_appendix.edd.fm</filepath> file
and change all instances of “title.0” to “title-appendix.0”, then
save the EDD.</li>
<li>In the appendix template (<filepath status = "changed">book_1.2_appendix.template.fm</filepath>)
rename the “title.0” style to “title-appendix.0” and modify its
appearance as needed.</li>
<li>Import the EDD into the appendix template, then save and close
both files.</li>
<li>Copy the appendix template to the proper component template
name (from <filepath status = "changed">book_1.2_appendix.template.fm</filepath> to <filepath>tpl~appendix.fm</filepath>,
then copy this file into the appropriate component template folders
(defined by the BookTemplatesDir parameter in the <filepath conref
= "ditafmx_shared.xml#common/bookbuild-ini"></filepath> file).</li></ol><p>When
a book is generated and this template is applied, this will apply
the title-appendix.0 style to the top-level heading in the appendix
files.</p></dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Add the new paragraph style to the GeneratedFile-toc
section</dt>
<dd><p>For each new TOC entry type, you’ll need to add that paragraph
style to the GeneratedFile-toc section of the <filepath conref =
"ditafmx_shared.xml#common/bookbuild-ini"></filepath> file. Be sure
to update the NumTags parameter to match the number of paragraph
tags used to generate the TOC.</p></dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Add support for the new TOC styles in the TOC template</dt>
<dd>In the TOC generated list template (“<filepath>gentpl~toc.fm</filepath>”),
add support for the “title-appendix.0TOC” style on the TOC reference
page (it would look just like the title.0TOC style but use the new
style name and prepend “Appendix” instead of “Chapter.” It should
also probably use an alpha numbering style instead of Roman.</dd></dlentry></dl>
<p>You can use the method described above to handle as many alternate
TOC entry types that you need in your book.</p></body></topic>
