<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="admin"?><?dtall dict="apps\\DITA"?><?dtall dict="Files\Adobe\FrameMaker\DITA"?><?dtall
dict="STRUCTDIR\\xml\\DITA"?><?dtall dict="XSLTProcessors"?><concept
    id = "idb62f0002-1e12-400f-a28a-a48ed67fcda7" status = "new"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Special Instructions for FM 2015</title>
<shortdesc status = "new">The default XSLT processor changed with
the FM13.0.1 update, which requires some extra work when setting
up the Book structure application.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>scottp</author>
<critdates status = "changed"><created date = "2015-09-10"/>
<revised modified = "2015-09-11"/></critdates></prolog>
<conbody><p status = "new">The DITA-FMx Book structure application’s
XSLT import script requires the XALAN processor, and with the FM13.0.1
update, the default has been changed to SAXON (the default can be
changed by modifying a setting in the <filepath status = "new">maker.ini</filepath> file).
The Generate Book from Map command makes use of the Book structure
application, and if the wrong processor is used, that command will
fail.</p>
<p status = "new">In order to ensure that the right processor is
used, a new element, Processor, was added to the structure application
definition EDD model. While this element is available after installing
the update, in the “global” structapps file (<menucascade status = "new">
<uicontrol status = "new">Structure Tools</uicontrol>
<uicontrol status = "new">Edit Global Application Definitions</uicontrol></menucascade>),
it may not be available in the “local” (user’s) structapps file
(<menucascade status = "new"><uicontrol status = "new">Structure
Tools</uicontrol><uicontrol status = "new">Edit Application Definitions</uicontrol></menucascade>).</p>
<p status = "new">If you’re installing DITA-FMx for the first time,
and you’ve got the 13.0.1 (or later) update for FM 2015, allowing
the structure applications to be installed as part of the default
workflow will ensure that the right files are installed; no further
effort on your part is needed.</p>
<p status = "new">However, if you’re using custom structure applications
or already have the DITA-FMx apps installed, you’ll need to perform
some manual updates in order for things to work properly.</p>
<p status = "new">Because of the variety of possible installation
scenarios, there is no “step-by-step” process that can be used to
fix this problem. The easiest fix is to open the <filepath
    status = "new">maker.ini</filepath> file and change the “Default”
from SAXON to XALAN (in the XSLTProcessors section). However, if
you want to be able to use SAXON in other contexts, you'll need
to jump through a few more hoops to get things working properly.</p>
<p status = "new">If you’re using the default DITA-FMx Book app,
you can just delete the Book entry in the structapps file and import
the new “stub” file that’s been modified for FM13.0.1 (<filepath
    status = "new">structapps-stub_book_1.2_13.0.1.fm</filepath>)
When you do this you’ll notice that the new Processor element is
flagged as being invalid. This is because the structapps file doesn’t
have the new EDD model. To fix this, open the stub file in FrameMaker, and
import the EDD from that file into the structapps file (<menucascade
    status = "new"><uicontrol status = "new">File</uicontrol>
<uicontrol status = "new">Import</uicontrol><uicontrol status = "new">Element Definitions</uicontrol></menucascade>).</p>
<p status = "new">If you’re using a custom structure application,
a similar process is needed. First, open your custom stub file,
and import the EDD from the <filepath status = "new">structapps-stub_book_1.2_13.0.1.fm</filepath> stub
file into your file. Then modify the PreProcessing element to include
the new Processor/XALAN elements. (If you’re not using a stub file,
do this directly in the structapps file.) After updating the stub
file, re-import that into the structapps file. You’ll need to import
the EDD from the stub file into the structapps file to get the EDD
model updated there as well.</p>
<p status = "new">Save the structapps file and restart FrameMaker,
then try a book-build. If you performed the necessary updates, all
should work fine.</p></conbody></concept>
