<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="project_a"?><topic id = "id08C8E60035Z"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Create Archive</title>
<shortdesc>Creates a ZIP archive of the current file and all referenced
files.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-12-08"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-31"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p>The Create Archive command uses the command line syntax
specified in the Archive field of the DITA Options: External Applications
dialog to create a ZIP archive of all files referenced by the current
file or map. This is an ideal way to create an archive of a project
at a given point in time or makes it easy to package up a project
to hand off to others.</p>
<p>When the command completes, a dialog displays the name of the
archive file created. The archive generated is named <filepath>&lt;filename>_zip.zip</filepath>,
where &lt;filename> is the root file name of the current file when
the Create Archive command is used. For example, if the archive
is created from the <filepath>project_a.ditamap</filepath> file,
the archive created will be named <filepath>project_a_zip.zip</filepath>.</p>
<p>If you’d like to include additional files in the archive that
are not specifically referenced (such as ditaval files), you can
create an “archive baggage” file. When the Create Archive command
runs, it checks in the folder of the current file for a file named <filepath>&lt;filename>-archive.txt</filepath> and
if this file is found, it includes the files listed in the new archive.
For example, if the archive is created from the <filepath>project_a.ditamap</filepath> file,
the command checks for a file named <filepath>project_a-archive.txt</filepath>.
This TXT file should list each baggage file on a separate line.
The file names are assumed to be relative to the current folder.</p>
<p status = "changed">By default DITA-FMx uses an open source archive
utility called “Info-ZIP.” The default file name of this utility
has been renamed to <filepath>ditafmx-zip.exe</filepath> and is
installed to the DITA-FMx installation folder (in the Program Files
area). You can specify an alternate archive utility or use different
command line options, by changing the command line syntax in the
DITA Options: External Applications dialog.</p>
<note id = "id4de0563c-dac4-4e17-aa76-6356b853ab27" status = "changed">If
the archive is not created, verify that the Command Line Syntax
value in the DITA Options: External Applications dialog is valid.
Deleting this value will reset it to the default value. You can
test by running the <filepath>~tmpzip.bat</filepath> batch file
in the user’s DITA-FMx folder (<menucascade status = "new">
<uicontrol status = "new">DITA-FMx</uicontrol>
<uicontrol status = "new">Open DITA-FMx Folder</uicontrol></menucascade>);
run this from a command shell to see any errors that may display.</note></body></topic>
