<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "idee670175-2865-4577-9a94-9bbeb8b6ab12"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Doctype/Application Mapping</title>
<shortdesc>Associate individual structure applications with each
topic type.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "2011-02-26"/>
<revised modified = "2015-09-08"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "changed"><p status = "new"><indexterm status = "new">doctype-application
mapping</indexterm><indexterm status = "new">topic-based structure
applications</indexterm>The <uicontrol status = "new">Doctype/Application
Mapping</uicontrol> dialog lets you associate individual structured applications
with each topic type (or doctype). The default DITA-FMx structured application
provides support for all of the main DITA topic types in a single
application. This simplifies template and EDD maintenance, but does
mean that all of the topics use the same doctype, ditabase.</p>
<p status = "new">If you want to maintain the applications separately
or need to use the topic-specific doctypes, you should use the doctype/application
mapping feature.</p>
<fig audience = "web"><title>Doctype/App Mapping dialog box</title><image
href="images/options-appmapping.png" align="left" placement="break"
 otherprops = "fmdpi:110"/></fig>
<p>The mapped doctypes (or topic types) are shown in the scrolling
list box. The application type is indicated by a letter in square
brackets, an “M” for maps or a “T” for topics, followed by the doctype
name, then the structured application name.</p>
<dl><dlentry><dt>Add</dt>
<dd>To add a doctype mapping, enter the doctype and select the structure
application from the list. Select the application type (map or topic)
and choose the Add button. The new mapping is added to the bottom
of the list.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Change</dt>
<dd>To modify an existing doctype mapping, select the mapping from
the list. The doctype, structure application, and application type
values populate the fields in the bottom of the dialog box. Modify
those fields as needed, then choose the Change button.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Delete</dt>
<dd>To delete a doctype mapping, select the mapping from the list
then choose the Delete button.</dd></dlentry></dl>
<p>When you are done making changes to the mappings, choose the
Save button.</p>
<p otherprops = "fm100-110" status = "changed">If you are using
FM10 or later, the mapping you define will be added to the default FrameMaker <filepath>ditafm.ini</filepath> file
in a new section named “DITA-FMx_1.1_Applications”. Also, by default,
the DITA version will be set to “DITA 1.1” (even for DITA 1.2 apps).</p>
<p status = "changed">Also, on FM10 and later, you may need to restart
FrameMaker after changing structure applications to ensure that
the proper structure applications have been registered in the <filepath>ditafm.ini</filepath> file.
Due to changes in these FrameMaker versions, the structure applications
are stored in both the <filepath>ditafmx.ini</filepath> and the
default <filepath>ditafm.ini</filepath> files.</p></body></topic>
