<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="SaveAs"?><?dtall dict="UniqueID"?><?dtall dict="xml:lang"?><topic
    id = "id07BHG0O075Z"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Generate Book from Map</title>
<shortdesc>Generates a FrameMaker book and chapter files from the
current DITA map.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-02-24"/>
<revised modified = "2014-04-03"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "changed"><p status = "changed">This command builds
a FrameMaker book by creating FM binary files from each top-level
topic reference in a DITA map. Any topic references within a <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">frontmatter</synph> or <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">backmatter</synph> wrapper
element are considered “top-level” topic references and become separate
FM files. Additionally, if your bookmap uses a <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">part</synph> element to organize chapters,
the file referenced by the <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">part</synph> will
become a separate FM file, and each child topic-referencing element
in the <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">part</synph> will
be considered a top-level topic reference and will be added to the
book after the generated part file.</p>
<p status = "changed">If the current DITA map file has not been
saved, it will be saved before processing begins. This command displays
the <uicontrol>Generate Map from Book</uicontrol> dialog, which
lets you specify the name and location of the book to be generated
as well as the ability to select a ditaval file and set an alternate
component template folder. You can also edit the associated book-build
INI file (<filepath status = "new">ditafmx-bookbuild.ini</filepath>)
or modify the default build settings from this dialog.</p>
<note type = "tip">The only required setting in this dialog is the <uicontrol>Book
File</uicontrol> name. If you want a quick test of the build process,
just specify the book file location and the book and component FM
files will be created there. A common practice is to create a folder named
“<filepath>book”</filepath> within the DITA project folder.</note>
<fig audience = "web print" status = "new"><title>Generate Book
from Map dialog</title><image href="images/generate-book.png" align="left"
placement="break"  otherprops = "fmdpi:110"/></fig>
<p status = "new">If you don’t want to be prompted when overwriting
files from a previous build, deselect the <uicontrol>Prompt to overwrite</uicontrol> option
and if you want the build log (console file) to automatically open
after the build completes, select the <uicontrol>Open console file</uicontrol> option. If
the path specified for the book file does not exist, it will be
created for you.</p>
<p>The <uicontrol>Component Template Folder Override</uicontrol> option
lets you specify an alternate location from which to read the component
templates for the build. Similarly, the <uicontrol>Ditaval Override</uicontrol> option
lets you select an alternate ditaval file. The default for both of
these settings is defined in the book-build INI file (either local
or default). The default ditaval can also be set in the Book Build
Settings dialog (although the value in the book-build INI will override
that in Settings).</p>
<p status = "new">Once the book file name has been set, the <uicontrol>Edit
INI</uicontrol> button opens the “local” book-build INI file which
provides advanced options for controlling details of the book component
creation. If no book-build INI file exists in the specified book
output folder, the <uicontrol>Edit INI</uicontrol> button copies
the default book-build INI to this location before opening it for
editing. The <uicontrol>Delete INI</uicontrol> button is provided
to remove the local INI file. If no book-build INI file exists in
the book output folder, the settings are read from the default location
or from the <uicontrol>Book Build Settings</uicontrol> dialog (the
settings in the book-build INI override those in the Settings dialog).</p>
<p>If the <uicontrol>Use Language Templates</uicontrol> option is
enabled (in the Options dialog), a language-specific book-build
INI file is read (if one exists). The language is determined by
the <synph outputclass = "attribute">xml:lang</synph> value in the
map. For example, if the <synph outputclass = "attribute">xml:lang</synph> value
is “de-de”, the book-build INI file name would be <filepath>ditafmx-bookbuild.de-de.ini</filepath>.</p>
<p status = "new">The book build process starts by aggregating the
DITA topic files referenced by the map and any submaps into a single
XML file which is imported into FrameMaker using the “Book” structure
application which creates the book and chapter files. The resulting
FM files are named based on the root topic file’s relative path
and filename with a “.fm” file extension.</p>
<p status = "new">If your map contains key definitions, a keyspace
will be generated based on the selected ditaval file (if any). The
default keyspace is reset after the build process completes.</p>
<p status = "changed">Before using this command you should select
the desired options in the Book Build Settings dialog, or carefully
set up the book-build INI file for this project. The options specified
in the Book Build Settings dialog are used for all book builds unless
overridden by settings in a book-build INI file. This INI file is
read from the same folder as the generated book file or in the user’s
DITA-FMx folder (<menucascade status = "new"><uicontrol status = "new">DITA-FMx</uicontrol>
<uicontrol status = "new">Open DITA-FMx Folder</uicontrol></menucascade>).</p>
<p status = "new">Many of the more advanced options, such as numbering
and pagination, must be set manually in the book-build INI file.
You can maintain separate book-build INI files for each project,
or one common INI in the user’s DITA-FMx folder.</p>
<p status = "changed">Conrefs and xrefs that reference content within
the book, are updated to point to the new FM files. Any references
to DITA files that are not part of the final book, remain pointing
at the source DITA file (with the href attribute modified to suit
the new path if it has changed). The paths to referenced graphics
are updated to account for any changes due to relative differences
between the source files and the location of the generated FM files.
If your files do reference files that are not part of the book (typically
graphics and possibly conrefs), it is important to choose an appropriate
location to generate the book so that the FM files and referenced
files can be easily moved as needed.</p>
<note>It is not uncommon to get “XML Parser Messages” in the “XML
Read Report Log” regarding IDs that have been “already used.” This
happens if you’ve used a conref multiple times and that conref contains
an ID that is of type “UniqueID.” Frame doesn’t like multiple instances
of the same UniqueID in the same document. DITA doesn’t care since
they are in different topics. If you get this message, just choose
the “OK” button and proceed.</note>
<section><title>Maintaining a generated book</title><p
    status = "changed">One possible way to build and maintain a
custom book is described below. The use of a <filepath>ditafmx-bookbuild.ini</filepath> file
and component templates should obviate the need to maintain a book
in the way, but this method is offered as an alternative.</p><ol><li><p>Generate
the book and FM files with the Generate Book from Map command. Think
of this as a “throw-away” book, and name it something temporary
like <filepath>temp.book</filepath>.</p></li>
<li><p>Create a new book by doing a SaveAs from the throw-away book.
This is your “real” book, give it an appropriate name.</p></li>
<li><p>Add your TOC, Index, and other non-DITA-based files to the
“real” book.</p></li>
<li><p>Setup the properties for each file in the “real” book. Select
each file and right-click, then choose Numbering, Pagination, or
Set Up, as appropriate.</p></li>
<li><p>Now choose <menucascade><uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol><uicontrol>Update
Book</uicontrol></menucascade> to generate your TOC and Index.</p></li>
<li><p>Save the “real” book.</p></li></ol><p>Now, when you update
your DITA files, re-run the Generate Book from Map command and overwrite
the “throw-away” book and the FM content files will be replaced
with fresh versions. Just close the “throw-away” book file that’s
been generated, then open your “real” book and do an <menucascade>
<uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol><uicontrol>Update</uicontrol></menucascade> to
refresh the TOC and Index and your book is ready to print.</p></section></body></topic>
