<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "id0833I0F01HS"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Required Element Definitions</title>
<shortdesc>To make the most of the authoring and publishing features
in DITA-FMx, some elements must be set up in a specific manner.
This topic describes those requirements.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-03-03"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-29"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p status = "changed">The easiest way to get up and running
with DITA in FrameMaker is to use the default structure applications
provided with DITA-FMx; they will “just work” right out of the box.
Once you’re comfortable with things and want to make some adjustments
to fit your house style or want to specialize, you can either clone
the apps provided, use some DITA apps provided by someone else,
or make your own from scratch.</p>
<p status = "new">If you want to customize the apps provided with
DITA-FMx, refer to the topic <xref href = "ditafmx_customizingapps.xml#id0837A060NHS"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref>. If you want
to use other applications or want to make your own, just be sure
that they adhere to the requirements expected by DITA-FMx. In order
to implement certain DITA features in DITA-FMx, the applications
must be set up in a very specific way.</p>
<p>The information in the following topics describes the requirements
that need to exist in a DITA structure application so that it functions
properly with DITA-FMx. All of the modifications described affect
the structure application files only (EDD, template, rules file),
no modifications need to be made to the DITA DTD files. The items
are grouped by feature, some of these features require the addition
of multiple elements or structure application modifications. If
you don’t want to make use of a given feature, you can skip the
modifications described in that section. There are many other rules
and EDD modifications that are needed for proper use of DITA files
in FrameMaker, these are not discussed; only those features that
are required or used by DITA-FMx are documented at this time.</p>
<p>The easiest way to set up these features in your custom application
is to copy and paste from the default DITA-FMx applications.</p></body></topic>
