<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="APIs"?><?dtall dict="ArchiveCommandLine"?><?dtall dict="AssignIdToElem"?><?dtall
dict="AttrAsCondDefaultState"?><?dtall dict="addon"?><?dtall dict="app"?><?dtall
dict="BookBuildOverrides"?><?dtall dict="Booklists"?><?dtall dict="BuildFile"?><?dtall
dict="backmatter"?><?dtall dict="bookbuild"?><?dtall dict="CallClient"?><?dtall
dict="DitaFMxGuide"?><?dtall dict="DitaReference"?><?dtall dict="DitaRefTargetPath"?><?dtall
dict="DitavalName"?><?dtall dict="DLLs"?><?dtall dict="desc"?><?dtall dict="dita"?><?dtall
dict="ditafmx"?><?dtall dict="ditavals"?><?dtall dict="doctype"?><?dtall
dict="FrameMaker\DITA"?><?dtall dict="figurelist"?><?dtall dict="fmx"?><?dtall
dict="fragref"?><?dtall dict="frontmatter"?><?dtall dict="GeneralExport"?><?dtall
dict="IgnoreFigTitleProcessing"?><?dtall dict="ImportAttrsAsVars"?><?dtall
dict="INIOnly"?><?dtall dict="InstallApps"?><?dtall dict="indexlist"?><?dtall
dict="LastReferencedElement"?><?dtall dict="Linebreak"?><?dtall dict="linebreaks"?><?dtall
dict="linktext"?><?dtall dict="MoveFigureTitles"?><?dtall dict="omsyshome%\common\bin"?><?dtall
dict="outputclass"?><?dtall dict="PageStartSide"?><?dtall dict="RegInfo"?><?dtall
dict="Reimport"?><?dtall dict="ReimportTemplate"?><?dtall dict="reflabel"?><?dtall
dict="reimports"?><?dtall dict="relinked"?><?dtall dict="SuiteHelp"?><?dtall
dict="SuppressXrefAttrs"?><?dtall dict="suitehelp"?><?dtall dict="synnoteref"?><?dtall
dict="syntaxdiagram"?><?dtall dict="toc"?><?dtall dict="type=’fm"?><?dtall
dict="UseOutputclassForType"?><?dtall dict="WriteLineBreakPIs"?><?dtall
dict="WriteLineBreakPIsInPre"?><?dtall dict="webhelp"?><?dtall dict="whitespace"?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Topicmeta Red NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Prolog AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Comment AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_SYSTEM_HIDEELEMENT AsIs NO_OVERRIDE hide?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_TRACK_CHANGES_ADDED Forest%20Green SINGLE_UNDERLINE show?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_TRACK_CHANGES_DELETED Red STRIKETHROUGH show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Data AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>

<?Fm BoolCondExpr "" State 0?>


<?Fm TrackChange Off PreviewState PREVIEW_OFF_TRACK_CHANGE?>
<topic id = "id5a8568e2-9ca6-43d8-9747-36354b3b8d96"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>1.1.14 - 31 January 2012</title>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "2011-08-03"/>
<revised modified = "2012-02-06"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><section status = "changed"><title outputclass = "h3">New
Features</title><dl><dlentry><dt>Default structure applications
are automatically installed</dt>
<dd>On a new installation of DITA-FMx, the default structure applications
are installed on the first use of FrameMaker.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>New CallClient APIs have been added</dt>
<dd>The “InstallApps” API is now available for use by other applications
to automatically install structure applications. This API does not
require the use of the FMx-Auto addon.</dd>
<dd>The “AssignIdToElem” API is now available for use by other applications
to assign an ID to the specified or selected element in a document.
This API does require the use of the FMx-Auto addon.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Integration with the FMx-Auto addon</dt>
<dd>This DITA-FMx update is the minimum version that can be used
with the FMx-Auto addon. FMx-Auto is a separate plugin that enables
the API in DITA-FMx to allow automated PDF (and other) publishing
options.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Integration with DITA2Go</dt>
<dd>If you have DITA2Go installed, a “DITA2Go Project Manager” menu
item will be available on the DITA-FMx menu. (This checks for the
%OMSYSHOME% environment variable and the existence of the <filepath>d2gpm.exe</filepath> file
at %omsyshome%\common\bin.)</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Integration with SuiteHelp DITA-OT plugin</dt>
<dd>The <filepath>ditafmx-ant.xml</filepath> file has been updated
to include a “suitehelp” target. If you have the <xref href = "http://www.suite-sol.com/pages/solutions/suitehelp.html"
format = "html" scope = "external">SuiteHelp DITA-OT plugin</xref> installed
(from Suite Solutions), you’ll be able to generate the SuiteHelp
webhelp output from the DITA-FMx Generate Output dialog.</dd>
<dd>If you are upgrading DITA-FMx, in order to take advantage of
this integration, in addition to installing the SuiteHelp plugin
you’ll need to do the following:<ul><li><p>Copy the updated <filepath>ditafmx-ant.xml</filepath> file
into your DITA-OT folder then run the DITA-OT <filepath>startcmd.bat</filepath> file
and integrate the new <filepath>ditafmx-ant.xml</filepath> file
by running: <codeph>ant-f integrator.xml</codeph></p></li>
<li><p>Update your <filepath>ditafmx.ini</filepath> file by adding
a new “suitehelp” entry to the BuildFile section (be sure to update
the “Count” parameter as well)</p></li></ul></dd></dlentry></dl></section>
<section status = "changed"><title outputclass = "h3">Structure
Application Updates</title><p>None.</p></section>
<section><title outputclass = "h3">Bug Fixes / Minor Updates</title><dl
    status = "changed"><dlentry status = "new"><dt status = "new">Updated
the version of the import/export client to 1.1.14</dt>
<dd status = "new">Previously, the two plugin DLLs were not in sync;
they were updated separately as needed when their code was changed.
In an effort to reduce confusion, both DLLs will now have the same
version number regardless of any changes to the underlying code. The
import/export client would have been version 1.1.12 with this release,
but it is now set to 1.1.14 to match the authoring client DLL.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry status = "new"><dt status = "new">XML Read Report messages
no longer report missing images in book build</dt>
<dd status = "new">Previously, images were reported as missing even
though they would typically be relinked to the proper file location
during the book-build process. Missing images are now replaced with
a default “missing” image file on file open. This process prevents the
XML Read Report window from displaying when no real problem exists.
The default missing image is defined by the value of the image/@placement
attribute, and is one of the two files (installed in the <filepath>FrameMaker\DITA-FMx</filepath> folder) <filepath>missing-image-break.png</filepath> or <filepath>missing-image-inline.png</filepath>.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry status = "new"><dt status = "new">Use ditavals in Book
Build process without registering the ditaval file</dt>
<dd status = "new">The DitavalName parameter now accepts a file
name in addition to the registered ditaval name. This simplifies
the use of alternate ditaval files for book builds.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry status = "new"><dt status = "new">Added new Book Build
setting for controlling conditions</dt>
<dd status = "new">New General/AttrAsCondDefaultState INI parameter
defines the default Hide/Show state for all “fmx-” conditions. Significantly
updated the related documentation on this topic, see <xref href
= "ditafmx_fmditabook_attributes.xml#id1094G010FBF" type = "topic"
format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref> and <xref href = "ditafmx_addingnewfmditabookattributes.xml#id3a2152b0-95cf-4a97-9f6a-2921c293cc2a"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref>.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry status = "new"><dt status = "new">New maps are opened in
document view</dt>
<dd status = "new">For FM9/10 if the “Open maps in document view”
option is enabled, newly created maps are now opened in document
view.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry status = "new"><dt status = "new">Fixed problem with writing
of duplicate document dictionary PIs</dt>
<dd status = "new">If the structure application template contained
document dictionary entries, each time you open and save a file,
the entries would get duplicated as processing instructions in the
DITA file. Now if a file contains duplicate document dictionary
entries, only one instance is written as a PI.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry status = "new"><dt status = "new">Added support for proper
whitespace handling around conrefs and xrefs</dt>
<dd status = "new">Recompiled the FM10 import/export client with
the updated FM10 FDK to incorporate fixes provided by Adobe regarding
whitespace handling in FM10.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry status = "new"><dt status = "new">Corrected problems when
using nesting separators in see-also index entries</dt>
<dd status = "new">Resolved data corruption when an indexterm used
two or more “nesting separators.” Previously, if a see-also entry
made use of more than two reference terms, indexterm elements would
not import properly and would thus be lost on file save..</dd>
<dd>A semicolon can now be defined as a see-also nesting separator.
When specifying this type of separator be sure to use a slash-semicolon
(“\;”).</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Conrefs to tables and footers now properly round trip
with the XDocs CMS</dt>
<dd>Previously, conrefs to table and sub-table elements as well
as footer elements were not being properly converted into CMS-based
paths. XDocs refused to allow these files to be checked in.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Attribute selection in the Set Attributes dialog remains
correct when switching elements </dt>
<dd>Previously, when using the Set Attributes command, changing
the element selection would cause the selected attribute to change
incorrectly. This no longer happens.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>External links with a desc element format properly</dt>
<dd>Previously, if an external link contained a desc element, the
text of the desc element was merged with the linktext element. This
no longer happens.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Fixed problems with fragref and synnoteref elements</dt>
<dd>When fragref and synnoteref elements are used, they no longer
are assigned the @type, @scope, and @format attributes (invalid
for these elements). Also, when synnoteref is written to XML, it
is now correctly written as an empty element. Note that there are
still some EDD and functional issues with the syntaxdiagram child elements,
however they should all round trip properly. (These remaining issues
will be addressed in a future release.)</dd>
<dd>Because fragref and synnoteref are specializations of the xref
element, the @type, @scope, and @format attributes would be added
when written to XML, to prevent this from happening, a new <filepath>ditafmx.ini</filepath> setting
has been added to the INIOnly section. Use the SuppressXrefAttrs
parameter to specify elements that should not have these attributes
added. If this parameter is not set, this value defaults to “fragref
synnoteref”.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>syntaxdiagram/title is not treated as a figure title</dt>
<dd>Because syntaxdiagram inherits from fig, its title was moved
when the MoveFigureTitles option is enabled. A new ditafmx.ini setting
has been added to prevent this from happening. INIOnly/IgnoreFigTitleProcessing
specifies a space-delimited list of fig-based elements to ignore.
By default this is set to “syntaxdiagram”.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Linebreak PIs are no longer added to preformatted elements</dt>
<dd>By default, a linebreak processing instruction is added to all
linebreaks entered into the document. These are not needed and in
fact redundant when included in elements based on the pre element
(such as screen and codeblock). These PIs are no longer added to
pre-based elements by default.</dd>
<dd>There are two new <filepath>ditafmx.ini</filepath> parameters
provided to control the linebreak PI feature. In the GeneralExport
section, the WriteLineBreakPIs parameter can be set to 1 or 0 to
enable or disable the writing of linebreak PIs (if not set this
defaults to 1, enabled). Also in the GeneralExport section, the
WriteLineBreakPIsInPre parameter can be set to 1 or 0 to enable
or disable the writing of linebreak PIs within pre-based elements (if
not set this defaults to 0, disabled). These parameters must be
manually set in the <filepath>ditafmx.ini</filepath> file.</dd></dlentry></dl></section></body></topic>
