<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [
]>
<?dtall dict="fm"?><?dtall dict="tpl~topicref"?><topic
    id = "id97325cf7-d095-4331-9c64-5617fd46d6e9"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Hazard Statement Publishing Options</title>
<shortdesc>To render <synph status = "changed" outputclass = "element">hazardstatement</synph> elements
for publishing, the default DITA elements are wrapped in a table
structure made up of a number of special <synph status = "changed"
    outputclass = "element">fm-*</synph> elements.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "2017-10-03"/>
<revised modified = "2017-11-10"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><note>The <synph status = "changed" outputclass = "element">fm-*</synph> elements
mentioned here are described in <xref href = "ditafmx_app_bookapplicationelements.xml#id466d7829-cb25-46ac-9015-ebd3a4a02729"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref>.</note>
<p status = "new"><indexterm status = "new">hazardstatement support</indexterm><indexterm>hazardstatement
element</indexterm><indexterm>elements<indexterm>hazardstatement</indexterm></indexterm>The
hazard table wrapping of <synph status = "changed"
    outputclass = "element">hazardstatement</synph> elements is
performed by default if the special <synph status = "changed"
    outputclass = "element">fm-*</synph> elements exist in the Book
structure application. To prevent this process from running, in
the bookbuild INI, set BookBuildOverrides/HazardToTable=0.</p>
<p>DITA-FMx supports two styles of hazard tables. One style has
a full-width header and a row below with two cells, one for the
hazard symbol and the other for the hazard information (<synph
    status = "changed" outputclass = "element">messagepanel</synph> structure).
The other style has a partial-width header where the hazard symbol
is in the first column, and the header and content in the second
column (this is the default style in the DITA-FMx Book templates).</p>
<fig><title>Full-width header hazard table style</title><image href="images/hazard-book-alt.png"
align="left" placement="break"  outputclass = "fmdpi:120"/></fig>
<fig><title>Partial-width header hazard table style (default)</title><image
href="images/hazard-book-default.png" align="left" placement="break"
 outputclass = "fmdpi:120"/></fig>
<p>During the hazard-to-table processing, each <synph
    outputclass = "element">hazardstatement</synph> element is replaced
with an <synph outputclass = "element">fm-hazardtable</synph> element
and the attributes are transfered from one to the other. Within
the <synph outputclass = "element">fm-hazardtable</synph> a <synph
    outputclass = "element">fm-hazardtgroup</synph> element is inserted
which inserts a “Hazard” table object. The default properties of
this table controls the appearance of the resulting hazard tables.
To create a full-width header table, the default layout should have
1 header row and 1 body row, with 2 columns. For a partial-width
header table, set up the default table layout with no header rows, 2
body rows and 2 columns.</p>
<fig><title>Structural model after hazard-to-table processing</title><image
href="images/hazard-book-struct.png" align="left" placement="break"
 outputclass = "fmdpi:120"/></fig>
<p>The header background coloring is controlled by a custom color
definition named based on the hazardstatement/@type attribute. Create
a custom color for each @type value you plan to use. These colors
should use the naming convention of “hazard-<i>TYPE</i>” (where
“<i>TYPE</i>” is the value of the <synph outputclass = "attribute">type</synph> attribute).
Hazard statements without a <synph outputclass = "attribute">type</synph> attribute
value will use a color named “hazard.”</p>
<p>The formatting and text of the header label is also tied to the <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">type</synph> attribute. A paragraph
tag is applied to the <synph status = "changed" outputclass = "element">fm-hazardhead</synph> element
using the naming convention of “hazard.head.<i>TYPE</i>” (and “hazard.head”
for no <synph outputclass = "attribute">type</synph> value). This paragraph
tag defines an autonum prefix for each label for the header text.</p>
<p><indexterm>hazardsymbol element</indexterm><indexterm>messagepanel
element</indexterm><indexterm>elements<indexterm>hazardsymbol</indexterm></indexterm><indexterm>elements<indexterm>messagepanel</indexterm></indexterm>The <synph
    status = "changed" outputclass = "element">hazardsymbol</synph> element
is inserted into the first column and wrapped in a <synph
    status = "changed" outputclass = "element">fm-hazardsymbolwrapper</synph> element.
This wrapper element is used even when there is no <synph
    status = "changed" outputclass = "element">hazardsymbol</synph> element
to allow custom formatting if needed. For the partial-width header
table, the top, left, and bottom rulings are set to “None” for the first
column, effectively making the symbol separate from the content
table.</p>
<p>The maximum width of hazardsymbol images is controlled by the
Max Symbol Width setting in the Authoring Options dialog. To override
this for a book build, use the BookBuildOverrides/HazardSymbolMaxWidth
parameter.</p>
<p>The <synph status = "changed" outputclass = "element">messagepanel</synph> element
(and children) are inserted into the second cell in the second row.
Additional <synph status = "changed" outputclass = "element">messagepanel</synph> elements
are inserted into extra rows in the table. Use typical EDD/template
formatting techniques for the <synph status = "changed"
    outputclass = "element">messagepanel</synph> elements. </p>
<p>If you are using the full-width header tables and want to create
separate table formats for each hazard type, you can use the header
background color defined in the default format rather than creating
custom color definitions. To do this, in the bookbuild INI set BookBuildOverrides/UseColorFromTable=1. </p>
<p>The default DITA-FMx Book application and component templates
all have the necessary settings, objects, and element definitions
to render the partial-width header hazard tables (this format appears
to be the most “standard”). If you’d like to test the full-width
header style, locate the <filepath>tpl~topicref-HAZALT.fm</filepath> file
in the Book application’s <filepath>component-templates</filepath> folder.
This file contains the styles and objects that will create a full-width
header style hazard table. If you’ve enabled the “Component Templates”
book-build option, and your component map element types are “topicrefs”
you can swap this file for the default topicref component template.
Or, if needed, rename it to be a chapter component template. To
set up other templates, you’ll need to copy and paste the Hazard
table into that template as well as transfer the color definitions
and paragraph definitions. </p></body></topic>
