<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="darkblue"?><?dtall dict="ForceTablesWide"?><?dtall dict="PreserveTableWidths"?><?dtall
dict="pgwide"?><?dtall dict="stentry"?><?dtall dict="tableformat"?><topic
    id = "id1429F0LD0YK"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Controlling Table Widths</title>
<shortdesc status = "changed">Tables will typically fill the available
text column width, but there are options if you need specific control
over table widths.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates status = "changed"><created date = "2009-02-08"/>
<revised modified = "2015-03-28"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "changed"><p>If you are using the default DITA-FMx
structure applications, all tables, regardless of their type, are
set to use proportional widths. This means that the table will expand
to fill the width of the current text column and all cells within
the table will proportionally fill the table based on the widths
you assign.</p>
<p>If you want to be able to specify absolute widths for tables,
you need to comment out or delete the <codeph>writer use proportional
widths</codeph> rule in the read/write rules files (<filepath
    status = "changed">topic_1.2.rules.txt</filepath> and <filepath
    status = "changed">book_1.2.rules.txt</filepath>). After commenting
this line out it will look like the following:</p>
<codeblock>/* writer use proportional widths; */</codeblock>
<note>This setting affects all tables of all types that use the
structure application associated with the rule file. You cannot
have some tables that are proportional and some that are absolute.</note>
<p status = "changed">You will also need to disable the <uicontrol>Force
Tables Wide</uicontrol> option in the <uicontrol>Authoring Options</uicontrol> dialog.</p>
<p status = "changed">If you’d like a specific table to fill the
width of the text frame (overriding the margins or indents), set
the <synph outputclass = "element">table</synph> element’s <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">pgwide</synph> attribute to 1. This
attribute is only available for tables that inherit from the base <synph
    outputclass = "element">table</synph> element.</p>
<p status = "new">An alternate option for defining table widths
that vary is through the use of the <uicontrol>Preserve Table Widths</uicontrol> option
in the <uicontrol>Authoring Options</uicontrol> dialog. This should
be used with <uicontrol>Force Tables Wide</uicontrol> enabled, and
will preserve the width of tables to the nearest 5%. A relative
table width value is stored in the table’s <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">pgwide</synph> attribute (this value
is updated on file save). </p>
<p status = "new">Use the <uicontrol>Preserve Table Widths</uicontrol> option
only if the “writer use proportional widths” rule is enabled, if
disabled, this feature is not needed. Because of the 5% adjustment on
save, column widths will not remain exactly as set (they will be
close though).</p>
<note type = "important">If you’re using the <uicontrol>Preserve
Table Widths</uicontrol> option, problems can occur if the text
flow width in the Topic and Book templates are not the same, because
the table width is preserved as a percentage of the text flow width.
The default DITA-FMx Topic and Book templates do not have matching
width text flows. Edit the Reference pages in Topic template to
set the text flow width to match that of the Book.</note></body></topic>
