<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="AssignMasterPagesFromMarkers"?><?dtall dict="BookBuildOverrides"?><?dtall
dict="fmx"?><?dtall dict="masterpage"?><?dtall dict="StructMasterPageMaps"?><?dtall
dict="UpdateBook"?><topic id = "id1248K0XN0Y4"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Custom Master Pages</title>
<shortdesc>Custom master pages can be applied to specific pages
throughout a book to provide alternate page layouts.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "2012-04-08"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-28"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p><indexterm>StructMasterPageMaps</indexterm><indexterm>master
page mapping</indexterm>By default, the structure application template
or the component template will apply one or more master pages to
a document based on the settings in the Master Page Usage dialog
(<menucascade><uicontrol>Format</uicontrol><uicontrol>Page Layout</uicontrol>
<uicontrol>Master Page Usage</uicontrol></menucascade>). If you
need to apply additional master pages to specific pages you can
use the standard FrameMaker custom master page mapping mechanism
through the StructMasterPageMaps table Reference page. This mapping
table lets you associate master pages to paragraph or element tags
and define very detailed mapping contexts. For information on this
feature, refer to the FrameMaker documentation.</p>
<p>In order for the StructMasterPageMaps mapping table to be applied
to the book components, you must select the <uicontrol>Apply Master
Pages</uicontrol> option in the Book Build Settings dialog or set
the BookBuildOverrides/UpdateBook parameter to “2” in the book-build
INI file. Setting this value to “1” updates the book, but does not
apply the mapping table.</p>
<p><data datatype = "fm:marker" name = "Comment" value = "zzz" />If
you’d like to apply the occasional master page without needing to
set up this mapping table, insert an fmx-masterpage marker with
the marker text set to the master page name to apply. Additionally,
you must set the BookBuildOverrides/AssignMasterPagesFromMarkers
parameter to “1” in the book-build INI file.</p>
<p status = "changed">You can use an unstructured fmx-masterpage
marker, which is stored in the DITA file as a processing instruction,
or you can use the <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">fm-data-marker</synph> element (which
is stored as a DITA <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">data</synph> element).
If you use the <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">fm-data-marker</synph> element,
you’ll need to create the fmx-masterpage marker definition in the
Topic and Book structure application templates (and potentially
any component templates that are used).</p>
<note>When using the <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">fm-data-marker</synph> element
as the fmx-masterpage marker, do not use the “Conditionalize data
and data-about" option along with "Hide Conditionalized Content"
option in the DITA-FMx Options dialog.</note></body></topic>
