<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "id6bcde90f-0635-4a66-90f6-345fc922822f"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Recommended Folder/File Structure</title>
<shortdesc status = "new">Tips for setting up folders and files
that will provide the desired results when generating books and
other types of output.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "2009-03-07"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-28"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "changed"><p status = "new">While, in theory, you
should be able to use any folder structure for your maps and topic
files, the default DITA-FMx Book application’s XSLT import script
is set up to work best with a specific structure as described below.</p>
<ul status = "new"><li status = "new">First and foremost, all files
must be on the same “drive,” and should be referenced with relative
path names. If you’re working on a shared server, be sure to always
access the files via a mounted drive letter. If you ever see drive
letters or UNC path descriptors (“\\SERVERNAME\PATH\...”), stop
and fix things so that you’re only seeing relative paths in the
source files.</li>
<li status = "new">Your root map should be in a parent folder or
the same folder as the topic or map files it references; a map should
not reference a topic through a folder “above” itself (the @href
attribute should never start with “../”). Although this will often
work, you may run into situations that it won’t, and if you’re planning on
generating CHM or other compiled Help output through the DITA-OT,
the map must always be at the root of the project.</li>
<li status = "new">Any submaps should also be in the same top-level
folder as the root map. This isn’t a hard requirement, and will
work in most cases with submaps in other folders, but if the folder
structure is very complex, the reference resolving process may fail.</li>
<li status = "new">Images and conrefs referenced by topics in the
project may be in folders above the root map, however if is best
to keep these in folders that are siblings or children of the root
map’s directory.</li></ul>
<p>The recommended folder structure for multiple projects is as
follows:</p>
<ul><li>A top-level folder (<filepath>dita-projects</filepath>)</li>
<li>Within the top-level folder are folders for the shared content
and the project folders themselves. Such as, <filepath>shared-images</filepath> (for
images that are shared among the projects), <filepath>shared-content</filepath> (for
conref source that is shared among the projects). If you have shared
topics, those may work in this folder as well, but certain output
types may not work well with that structure.</li>
<li>Within each project folder is a folder for topics (just one)
and a folder for images, as well as one or more “book” output folders
(one per book type).</li>
<li>Also in the project folder is the root map (possibly with an
underscore prefix so it sorts to the top) and all submaps. This
puts all of the maps in a separate folder from the topics and makes
them easily accessible.</li>
<li>Within each book output folder is that output type’s <filepath>component-templates</filepath> folder and
the <filepath>ditafmx-bookbuild.ini</filepath> file. This ensures
that building a book to that folder will always result in the same
output. If all of your books use the same component templates, you
may want to have a shared component templates folder.</li></ul>
<fig><title>Recommended folder structure</title><image href="images/folders.png"
align="left" placement="break"  otherprops = "fmdpi:110"/></fig></body></topic>
