<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [
]>
<task id = "id083UF70905Z"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Using the Apply Ditaval Command to Filter with Conditions</title>
<shortdesc>Steps for using a ditaval file to apply conditional filtering
to topics.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-03-30"/>
<revised modified = "2017-11-01"/></critdates></prolog>
<taskbody><prereq><p>When run interactively, the ditaval file must
be registered with DITA-FMx. To create a new ditaval file or register
an existing ditaval file, use the <uicontrol>Ditaval Manager</uicontrol> command.</p></prereq>
<steps><step><cmd>Open the document or book to apply the conditions.</cmd></step>
<step><cmd>Run the <menucascade><uicontrol>DITA-FMx</uicontrol>
<uicontrol>Utilities</uicontrol><uicontrol>Apply Ditaval</uicontrol></menucascade> command.</cmd></step>
<step><cmd>In the Apply Ditaval dialog, select the <uicontrol>Filter
with Conditions</uicontrol> option, then select the ditaval file
to use from the list box.</cmd></step>
<step><cmd>For each “action” type defined in the ditaval file, set
up the options in the appropriate “action=” section.</cmd>
<info><p>For example, if your ditaval file contains two prop elements where
each action attribute is set to “exclude”, you need to decide if
the condition to apply to the matching elements should be a specific
name (one name for all “excluded” elements) or if you want it to
apply a unique name for each prop element. If you’re OK with using
a single condition name, just select the radio button under Condition
Name and enter that name in the text box. If you’d like a unique
name for each prop element, select the “&lt;attribute>=&lt;value>”
radio button. This will make two conditions (one for each prop element),
and apply each to the corresponding elements.</p><p>Select the visibility
option for the condition. You can always change the visibility after applying
the conditions using the standard FrameMaker condition management commands.</p></info></step>
<step><cmd>Choose the OK button to apply the conditions.</cmd></step></steps></taskbody></task>
