<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="ANT:&lt;buildname"?><?dtall dict="AntBuild"?><?dtall dict="AntCommand"?><?dtall
dict="AntScript"?><?dtall dict="app"?><?dtall dict="BaselineOffset"?><?dtall
dict="BookTitleVariableName"?><?dtall dict="BuildFile"?><?dtall dict="booklists"?><?dtall
dict="booktitle"?><?dtall dict="buildname"?><?dtall dict="CMSClientName"?><?dtall
dict="CMSImageDefaultDpi"?><?dtall dict="CrossRefToXref"?><?dtall dict="CustomTableCount"?><?dtall
dict="DitaDir"?><?dtall dict="DitaFMxGuide"?><?dtall dict="DitaHelpKeys"?><?dtall
dict="DitaLinkElem"?><?dtall dict="DitaReference"?><?dtall dict="DitaRefTargetPath"?><?dtall
dict="DitaRefTargetPath>]&lt;eleme"?><?dtall dict="DitaRefTargetPath>]&lt;element"?><?dtall
dict="DitaRefTargetType"?><?dtall dict="DitavalFiles"?><?dtall dict="DitaXrefElem"?><?dtall
dict="DTDs"?><?dtall dict="ditabook"?><?dtall dict="ditafmx"?><?dtall dict="doctype>:&lt;key"?><?dtall
dict="EnvironmentSetup"?><?dtall dict="element>|&lt;cell"?><?dtall dict="element>|&lt;row"?><?dtall
dict="FlattenedConrefAttr"?><?dtall dict="FMxBookTitle"?><?dtall dict="FmDpiUseOutputclass"?><?dtall
dict="FmXrefUseOutputclass"?><?dtall dict="ForceTablesWide"?><?dtall dict="FrameMaker\DITA"?><?dtall
dict="fmdpi:N"?><?dtall dict="GeneralExport"?><?dtall dict="GeneralImport"?><?dtall
dict="IgnoreElemPrefix"?><?dtall dict="IndextermProcessing"?><?dtall dict="ja"?><?dtall
dict="Logfile"?><?dtall dict="MapFromOutlineTemplate"?><?dtall dict="MaxOpenFiles"?><?dtall
dict="MaxRefLevels"?><?dtall dict="MissingImageDir"?><?dtall dict="mainbooktitle"?><?dtall
dict="NewMapShortcuts"?><?dtall dict="NewTopicShortcuts"?><?dtall dict="new~&lt;topictype>~&lt;template"?><?dtall
dict="OutputDir"?><?dtall dict="pgwide"?><?dtall dict="pts"?><?dtall dict="RunaroundOff"?><?dtall
dict="SetAttrIgnore"?><?dtall dict="SetAttrStrings"?><?dtall dict="SetAttrStringsDefault"?><?dtall
dict="SetColumnsProp"?><?dtall dict="SetColumnWidthsProp"?><?dtall dict="Shift+Enter"?><?dtall
dict="STRUCTDIR\xml\DITA"?><?dtall dict="StripClassAttribute"?><?dtall dict="StripPadding"?><?dtall
dict="StripTrailing"?><?dtall dict="StructappsFile"?><?dtall dict="StructureDir"?><?dtall
dict="simpletable"?><?dtall dict="structapps"?><?dtall dict="TableImport"?><?dtall
dict="TableProcessing"?><?dtall dict="TplDelimChar"?><?dtall dict="tag>&lt;DitaRefTargetTy"?><?dtall
dict="tag>&lt;DitaRefTargetType"?><?dtall dict="UseBooklistPlaceholder"?><?dtall
dict="UseLanguageTemplate"?><?dtall dict="UseRefList"?><?dtall dict="Whitespace"?><?dtall
dict="WriteDictionaryPIs"?><?dtall dict="WriteLineBreakPIs"?><?dtall dict="WriteLinkTextToFmXrefs"?><?dtall
dict="XrefElements"?><?dtall dict="XrefElements=topic|concept|task|reference|section|dt"?><?dtall
dict="XrefProcessing"?><?dtall dict="xml:lang"?><topic
    id = "id067FF8008E9"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>INI-Only Settings</title>
<shortdesc>Describes the settings that must be applied manually
in the <filepath conref = "ditafmx_shared.xml#common/ditafm-ini"
class = "+ topic/ph sw-d/filepath "></filepath> file.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>test</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-02-18"/>
<revised modified = "2015-08-10"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "changed"><p id = "id1414G0HK05Z">The default values
for these parameters should be sufficient for most people, but there
are reasons that you may want to change the default behavior. The
following settings must be changed manually in the <filepath conref
= "ditafmx_shared.xml#common/ditafm-ini" class = "+ topic/ph sw-d/filepath
"></filepath> file.</p>
<dl status = "changed"><dlentry status = "changed">
<dt status = "changed">INIOnly section</dt>
<dd status = "new"><p status = "new"><indexterm status = "new">FlattenedConrefAttr,
INI parameter</indexterm><indexterm status = "new">flattened conref,
apply formatting</indexterm><indexterm status = "new">formatting
of flattened conrefs</indexterm><b status = "new">FlattenedConrefAttr</b> -
Specifies an attribute name to set on conref elements that have
been flattened during the book-build process. By default this is disabled
(set to an empty string), but if you set this to an attribute name
such as “outputclass”, that attribute will be set with the value
of “flattened-conref”. This can be useful if you want to apply formatting
to content that was previously a conref (but has been flattened).</p></dd>
<dd status = "changed"><p status = "new"><indexterm status = "new">MaxRefLevels,
INI parameter</indexterm><b status = "changed">MaxRefLevels</b> -
Specifies the number of nested files that are opened due to the
auto-loading of references (xref or conref). If your files never
have references within references (such as an xref within a conref),
then you should set this to a value of “1”. If your files do make
use of nested references, set this value equal to the maximum number
of reference levels that exist. The greater the number the longer
it may take to open files since all references in all opened files
will resolve (unless limited by this option). Valid values are 0
through 9 or “*” (asterisk means unlimited levels). Setting this
value to 0 disables the auto-updating of xrefs and conrefs. (Defaults
to “2” if this parameter is missing or set to a null string.)</p><p
    id = "id1414G0I0OY4" status = "new">This reference resolving
process is used when generating a book from a map, but is not used
while authoring unless the INIOnly/UseRefList parameter is set to
“0”.</p></dd>
<dd status = "changed"><p status = "changed"><indexterm>UseRefList,
INI parameter</indexterm><b status = "changed">UseRefList</b> -
Controls the way references are resolved while authoring. If set to
“1” (the default), references (xrefs and conrefs) are resolved “on
disk,” allowing for much faster processing and less time required
to open files. If set to “0” all referenced files are opened in
FrameMaker in order to resolve the references. The number of files
opened is determined by the reference nesting level, which is controlled
by the General/MaxRefLevels parameter. (Defaults to “1” if this
parameter is missing or set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>StructappsFile, INI parameter</indexterm><b>StructappsFile</b> -
Specifies an alternate file to use as the structure application definitions
file. In order for this to function properly you must also have
set the Directories/StructureDir parameter in the <filepath>maker.ini</filepath> file.
(No default value, may be null.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>XrefElements, INI parameter</indexterm><b>XrefElements</b> -
A vertical-bar delimited list of element names that defines the elements
that are valid as xref or link targets. For example, setting XrefElements
to the following string limits the xref targets to the elements
specified:</p><ul><li>XrefElements=topic|concept|task|reference|section|dt</li></ul><p>If
this parameter is not set, all elements are valid as xref or link
targets. (No default value, may be null.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>DitaFMxGuide, INI parameter</indexterm><b>DitaFMxGuide</b> -
Specifies the name of the DITA-FMx Help file (relative to the <filepath>FrameMaker\DITA-FMx</filepath> folder,
unless an absolute path is specified). This Help file may be a CHM
file or an EXE, or it may specify a URL (via the “http:” or “file:” protocols).
If an EXE is specified, this is likely an AIR Help file, but may
be any executable Help application set up to accept a command line
parameter that indicates the target HTML filename to display. (Defaults
to “ditafmx.chm” if this parameter is missing or set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>DitaHelpKeys, INI parameter</indexterm><b>DitaHelpKeys</b> -
Specifies the shortcut keystrokes to launch context-help for DITA
authoring (this runs the “DitaReference” Help file). The keys defined
here use the syntax for shortcuts as specified in the FDK Reference.
(Defaults to “~/F1”, Alt+F1, if this parameter is missing or set
to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>DitaReference, INI parameter</indexterm><indexterm>element-based
context sensitive Help</indexterm><indexterm>context sensitive Help</indexterm><b>DitaReference</b> -
Specifies the name of the DITA Reference Help file (relative to
the <filepath>FrameMaker\DITA-FMx</filepath> folder), which is used
for element-based context sensitive Help. This Help file may be
a CHM file or an EXE, or it may specify a URL (via the “http:” or
“file:” protocols). If an EXE is specified, this is likely an AIR
Help file, but may be any executable Help application set up to
accept a command line parameter that indicates the target HTML filename
to display. (Defaults to “ditafmx-ref.chm” if this parameter is
missing or set to a null string.)</p><p>Displaying the DITA Reference
Help uses a combination of this and two other parameters, DitaRefTargetType
and DitaRefTargetPath. If a DITA document is open and the insertion
point is within a DITA element, when the user presses Alt+F1 (as
defined by the DitaHelpKeys parameter), the following action is issued:</p><p>&lt;<i>DitaReference</i>>
[&lt;<i>DitaRefTargetPath</i>>]&lt;<i>element-tag</i>>&lt;<i>DitaRefTargetType</i>></p><p>If
the DitaReference parameter specifies a CHM or EXE file, the DitaRefTargetPath,
selected element tag name, and the DitaRefTargetType (file extension) values
are concatenated and passed to the Help system.</p><p>If the DitaReference
parameter specifies a URL, the DitaReference, DitaRefTargetPath,
selected element tag name, and the DitaRefTargetType (file extension) values
are concatenated and the resulting URL is passed to the default
web browser application.</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>DitaRefTargetType, INI parameter</indexterm><b>DitaRefTargetType</b> -
Specifies the file extension of target topics in the “DitaReference”
Help file for context sensitive Help. For additional information,
refer to the DitaReference parameter above. (Defaults to “.html”
if this parameter is missing or set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>DitaRefTargetPath, INI parameter</indexterm><b>DitaRefTargetPath</b> -
Specifies an optional “path” to target topics in the “DitaReference”
Help file for context sensitive Help. For additional information,
refer to the DitaReference parameter above. (No default value, may
be null.)</p></dd>
<dd><p status = "changed"><indexterm>MapFromListTemplate, INI parameter</indexterm><b>MapFromOutlineTemplate</b> -
Specifies the “Map from Outline” template file used as the template
for the <uicontrol>New ‘Map from Outline’ Template</uicontrol> command. (Defaults
to “$STRUCTDIR\xml\DITA-FMx_1.2\map-from-outline_template.fm” if
this parameter is missing or set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p status = "changed"><indexterm>BookTitleVariableName, INI
parameter</indexterm><b>BookTitleVariableName</b> - Specifies the
name of the variable that is updated with the book title (from map/title,
map/@title, bookmap/title, or bookmap/booktitle/mainbooktitle).
This variable is only updated in generated list files if it is included
in the generated list template (structured files can access the
book title via the attribute on the fm-ditabook element). (Defaults
to “FMxBookTitle” if this parameter is missing or set to a null
string.)</p></dd>
<dd status = "new"><p status = "changed"><indexterm>StripClassAttribute,
INI parameter</indexterm><b status = "changed">StripClassAttribute</b> -
Set this to “0” to prevent the @class attribute value from being
deleted when changing an element’s type (using the “Change” button
in the Element Catalog). (Defaults to “1”, enabled, if this parameter
is missing or set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd status = "new"><p status = "changed"><indexterm>TplDelimChar,
INI parameter</indexterm><b status = "changed">TplDelimChar</b> -
Set this to specify the character to use as the file name delimiter
for new file templates (<filepath status = "new">new~&lt;topictype>~&lt;template
name>.fm</filepath>), book-build component templates (<filepath
    status = "new">tpl~&lt;mapelemtype>.fm</filepath>), and generated
list templates (<filepath status = "new">gentpl~&lt;mapelemtype>.fm</filepath>).
If necessary you can set this to a character, such as the hash symbol,
#. (Defaults to “~” if this parameter is missing or set to a null
string.)</p></dd>
<dd status = "new"><p status = "changed"><indexterm>MaxOpenFiles,
INI parameter</indexterm><b status = "changed">MaxOpenFiles</b> -
Specifies the number of XML files opened before a warning is displayed.
This is convenience when working with FM7.2 and FM8 to allow time to
restart FrameMaker before it crashes. These versions of FrameMaker
have a bug that results in a crash after opening 300+ XML files
in the same session. (Defaults to “300” if this parameter is missing
or set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd status = "new"><p status = "changed"><indexterm>UseBooklistPlaceholder,
INI parameter</indexterm><b status = "changed">UseBooklistPlaceholder</b> -
Set this to “1” to revert to the pre 1.1.11 DITA-FMx method of requiring
a placeholder file to generate a list. The default value “0” indicates
that DITA-FMx will honor the “proper” syntax for frontmatter and backmatter
list elements which does not require a placeholder file.</p></dd>
<dd status = "new"><p status = "new"><indexterm>NewMapShortcuts,
INI parameter</indexterm><indexterm>NewTopicShortcuts, INI parameter</indexterm><indexterm
status = "new">new file shortcut keys</indexterm><indexterm status
= "new">shortcut keys, new files</indexterm><b status = "changed">NewMapShortcuts</b> and <b
    status = "new">NewTopicShortcuts</b> - Allows customization
of the shortcut keys assigned to the New File menu items. The value
for both of these is a space-delimited string of doctype/key pairs.
Use the following syntax:</p><p status = "new">&lt;doctype>:&lt;key-sequence></p><p
    status = "new">Where:</p><p status = "new">&lt;doctype> is the
root topic or map element.</p><p status = "new">&lt;key-sequence>
is the key sequence for the shortcut. To specify an ESC sequence
the string starts with “\!” (backslash, exclamation). This is followed by
2 or 3 characters or numbers (case sensitive). (In theory you can
also use ALT “~” or CTRL “^” or SHIFT “+”, but this may or may not
work well. You can also “try” to use function keys, which are defined
as slash followed by “F” and the number, as in “/F3”.)</p><p
    status = "new">For example, to create shortcuts for map, bookmap,
topic, and task, you could use the following:</p><codeblock status = "new" outputclass = "ini">NewMapShortcuts=map:\!NMM bookmap:\!NMB 
NewTopicShortcuts=topic:\!NTO task:\!NTA</codeblock></dd>
<dd status = "new"><p status = "changed"><indexterm>FilteringAttributes,
INI parameter</indexterm><b status = "changed">FilteringAttributes</b> -
Specifies the attributes that are considered when performing ditaval
filtering. The default value is a space-delimited string of attribute
names: <codeph>audience product platform otherprops rev props</codeph>.</p></dd></dlentry>
<dlentry id = "id13BNA0H0I5Z"><dt>INIOnly section (for use with
the Set Attributes command)</dt>
<dd><p><indexterm>SetAtt rIgnore, INI parameter</indexterm><b>SetAttrIgnore</b> -
Specifies the attributes to ignore (and not display) in the Set Attributes
dialog. This is a vertical bar delimited string. By default this
is set to the following values, you can change these values or set
this to a null string as needed.</p><codeblock expanse = "page">xtrc|xtrf|xmlns|class|xmlns:ditaarch|ditaarch:DITAArchVersion|domains</codeblock></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>SetAttrStrings, INI parameter</indexterm><b>SetAttrStrings</b> -
Specifies the “filtering groups” INI file which defines values for
the specified “Strings” attributes. These values are organized into
named groups which can be associated with a specific file system
path. All topic files that fall within the specified root path are
mapped to that group. Each group lists one or more attributes and
a vertical bar delimited list of default values for that attribute.
This lets you provide alternate filtering options for different
projects that use the same structure application without modifying
the EDD. (Defaults to “FilterGroups.ini” if this parameter is missing
or set to a null string.)</p><p>Unless the value of the SetAttrStrings
parameter specifies an absolute path and file name, it is relative
to the user’s DITA-FMx folder. If you use a SetAttrStrings file,
no default values need be set in the EDD at all. This adds flexibility
to the EDD not otherwise obtainable. For more information and details,
see <xref href = "ditafmx_ref_setattributes.xml#id083DA0A0WY4" type
= "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref>.</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>SetAttrStringsDefault, INI parameter</indexterm><b
    id = "id083DC0501PF">SetAttrStringsDefault</b> - Specifies the
“default” value that is ignored when displaying the list of defaults.</p><note>This
INI parameter is for very specialized and atypical use. Unless you are
doing special FDK processing using attributes of type “Strings”
you can safely ignore the following information.</note><p>When you
specify default values to a Strings attribute in the EDD, the first default
may be used as the actual default for certain types of processing.
If you want to specify a special value as the first default so that
your processing can match on it and ignore the value, enter that
string as the value for the SetAttrStringsDefault parameter. A likely
value is the dot (“.”) character, but you can specify any value
that makes sense for your processing. If you specify this value,
it will be ignored and excluded from the options displayed in the
Set Attribute dialog. (Defaults to “.” if this parameter is missing,
but this value may be set to a null string.)</p><p>If you do not
have processing that cares about the initial default value of a Strings
attribute, you can ignore this parameter.</p></dd></dlentry>
<dlentry id = "id13BNA0H0TY4" status = "changed">
<dt status = "changed">INIOnly section (for use with content management
systems)</dt>
<dd status = "changed"><p status = "changed"><indexterm>CMSClientName,
INI parameter</indexterm><b status = "changed">CMSClientName</b> -
Specifies the FDK client name used to connect with the CMS bridge
or connector. Typically set automatically by the CMS client. (No
default value, may be null.)</p></dd>
<dd status = "changed"><p status = "changed"><indexterm>CMSImageDefaultDpi,
INI parameter</indexterm><b status = "changed">CMSImageDefaultDpi</b> -
Specifies the default DPI for new images. Currently only used for
XDocs CMS. (Defaults to “72” if this parameter is missing or set to
a null string.)</p></dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt status = "changed">GeneralImport section</dt>
<dd><p><indexterm>IndextermProcessing (import), INI parameter</indexterm><b>IndextermProcessing</b> -
If set to 1, enables conversion of indexterm elements to proper
format required by FrameMaker. This parameter is set through the user
interface as the <option>Indexterm to Fm-indexterm Conversion</option> option
in the DITA-FMx Options dialog and should not be set manually without
care. (Defaults to “1” if this parameter is missing or set to a
null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>StripPadding, INI parameter</indexterm><b>StripPadding</b> -
If set to 1, strips leading space from the XML. This parameter is
set through the <option>Normalize Whitespace on Import</option> option
in the DITA-FMx Options dialog. (Defaults to “1” if this parameter
is missing or set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>StripTrailing, INI parameter</indexterm><b>StripTrailing</b> -
If set to 1, strips space characters from the XML that follow the opening
or closing block-level element tags. This only strips the spaces
when there are no other non-space characters in the node that follow
the open or close element. (Defaults to “1” if this parameter is
missing or set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>TableProcessing, INI parameter</indexterm><b>TableProcessing</b> -
If set to 1, enables the counting of table columns for proper import
of simpletable and other table types into FrameMaker. (Defaults
to “1” if this parameter is missing or set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>MissingImageDir, INI parameter</indexterm><b>MissingImageDir</b> -
Specifies the folder that the “missing image” files are stored.
This location is relative to the DITA-FMx folder in the Program
Files area, and defaults to “missing-images” if not specified. To
specify an alternate location, specify an absolute path to the folder
that contains these files. To disable this feature, set this parameter
to “0” (zero) or “Off”.</p><p>This feature is intended to eliminate
the XML parser log messages during a book-build that may incorrectly
report images as missing. This would often happen when generating
a book file into a folder structure that varies significantly from
that of the source folder structure. On import, the images would
in fact not be found, but the DITA-FMx “Reload References” book-build
option would resolve these references.</p><p>If enabled, during
the book-build process the images in the MissingImageDir folder
will temporarily replace the actual images to prevent the errant
XML parser log messages. This folder must contain a “break” and
“inline” image for each file type in use in your documents. These
files are named “missing-image-break.&lt;EXT>” and “missing-image-inline.&lt;EXT>”.</p></dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>GeneralExport section</dt>
<dd><p><indexterm>IndextermProcessing (export), INI parameter</indexterm><b>IndextermProcessing</b> -
If set to 1, enables conversion of indexterm elements from the format
required by FrameMaker back to one required by DITA. This parameter
is set through the user interface as the <option>Indexterm to Fm-indexterm Conversion</option> option
in the DITA-FMx Options dialog and should not be set manually without
care. (Defaults to “1” if this parameter is missing or set to a
null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>XrefProcessing, INI pa rameter</indexterm><b>XrefProcessing</b> -
If set to 1, enables processing and conversion of xrefs and links.
(Defaults to “1” if this parameter is missing or set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>CrossRefToXref, INI parameter</indexterm><b>CrossRefToXref</b> -
If set to 1, enables the conversion of FM-based cross-references
to DITA-based xrefs and links. (Defaults to “1” if this parameter
is missing or set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>DitaXrefElem , INI parameter</indexterm><b>DitaXrefElem</b> -
Defines the element name to use when mapping FM-based cross-refs
to DITA xrefs on file export (only used if GeneralExport/CrossRefToXref
is enabled). (Defaults to “xref” if this parameter is missing or
set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>DitaLinkElem, INI parameter</indexterm><b>DitaLinkElem</b> -
Defines the element name to use when mapping FM-based cross-refs
to DITA links on file export (only used if GeneralExport/CrossRefToXref
is enabled). (Defaults to “link” if this parameter is missing or
set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>IgnoreElemPrefix, INI parameter</indexterm><b>IgnoreElemPrefix</b> -
If you use elements in FrameMaker that do not exist in the DITA
DTDs, you should make sure they all have the same prefix (“fm-”
for example). This INI setting specifies that prefix. This is required
for proper generation of conrefs on export, and should be used in
conjunction with any read/write rules that may be needed. (Defaults
to “fm-” if this parameter is missing or set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>WriteLinkTextToFmXrefs, INI parameter</indexterm><b>WriteLinkTextToFmXrefs</b> -
If set to 1, specifies that the link text of fm-xrefs is written
to the xref element on file save. Normally, this link text is regenerated based
on the target element text, but if you want the FM-generated text
to be available for other processing engines, this should be enabled.
(Defaults to “0” if this parameter is missing or set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>WriteLineBreakPIs, INI parameter</indexterm><indexterm>dtall
break, processing instruction</indexterm><indexterm>processing instruction,
dtall break</indexterm><b>WriteLineBreakPIs</b> - If set to 1, specifies
that line breaks (Shift+Enter) are written to the XML file as a
processing instruction (PI). If DITA-FMx encounters a PI of <codeph>&lt;?dtall
break="line"?></codeph>, it inserts a line break, thus allowing
proper round-tripping of line breaks between authoring and publishing.
Note that the line breaks will only be persevered when publishing
through FrameMaker (and DITA-FMx), and other tools that honor this
processing instruction. (Defaults to “1” if this parameter is missing
or set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>WriteDictionaryPIs, INI parameter</indexterm><indexterm>document
dictionary</indexterm><indexterm>dictionary, document</indexterm><indexterm>dtall
dict, processing instruction</indexterm><indexterm>processing instruction,
dtall dict</indexterm><b>WriteDictionaryPIs</b> - If set to 1, specifies
that words flagged by the spelling checker as “Allow in Document”
are written to the XML file as a processing instruction (PI) before
the root topic node (<codeph>&lt;?dtall dict="allowed-word"?></codeph>). On
file open these words are loaded in to the document dictionary for
the current file. Note that these processing instructions are not
likely to be honored by other tools. (Defaults to “1” if this parameter
is missing or set to a null string.)</p><note>Over time if you clone
a topic file for other uses, these processing instructions may build
up in the file. You can delete the items in the document dictionary
for a given file by opening that file and choosing the Dictionaries button
in the Spelling Checker dialog. In that dialog select the Document Dictionary
option, choose Clear from the list, then choose OK.</note></dd>
<dd><p status = "changed"><indexterm>FmXrefUseOutputclass, INI parameter</indexterm><b>FmXrefUseOutputclass</b> -
If set to 1, specifies that <synph outputclass = "element">fm-xref</synph> elements
use the <synph outputclass = "attribute">outputclass</synph> attribute
rather than the <synph outputclass = "attribute">type</synph> attribute
to store the cross-ref format name. (In DITA-FMx 1.1 the default
was “0”, but now it is “1”.)</p></dd>
<dd><p status = "changed"><indexterm>FmDpiUseOutputclass, INI parameter</indexterm><indexterm>fmdpi
feature, attribute used</indexterm><b>FmDpiUseOutputclass</b> -
If set to 1, specifies that the “fmdpi” value is assigned to the <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">outputclass</synph> attribute rather
than the <synph outputclass = "attribute">otherprops</synph> attribute.</p><p
    status = "new">DITA-FMx 1.1 used the <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">otherprops</synph> attribute, which
was not the intended use for that attribute. Using the <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">outputclass</synph> attribute is more
in line with the DITA specification. This setting controls how this
attribute is added to new elements, but does not affect existing
elements. The sizing of images will work properly regardless of
the attribute the “fmdpi:<i>NN</i>” value is assigned.</p></dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>TableImport section</dt>
<dd><p><indexterm>SetColumnsProp, INI parameter</indexterm><b>SetColumnsProp</b> -
If set to 1, enables the automatic assignment of the “columns” property.
(Defaults to “1” if this parameter is missing or set to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>SetColumnWidthsProp, INI parameter</indexterm><b>SetColumnWidthsProp</b> -
If set to 1, enables the automatic assignment of the “column width”
property. (Defaults to “1” if this parameter is missing or set to a
null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>CustomTableCount, INI parameter</indexterm><b>CustomTableCount</b> and <b><i>N</i></b> -
Specifies the number of instances of simpletable elements that have
been specialized that need to be automatically analyzed for their
column number. The <i>Count</i> value should match the number of <i>N</i> values. Each <i>N</i> value
should have the following format: “&lt;table-element>|&lt;row-element>|&lt;cell-element>”.</p></dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>IndexOptions section</dt>
<dd><p><indexterm>IndexMarkerType, INI parameter</indexterm><indexterm>Japanese
index marker type</indexterm><b>IndexMarkerType</b> - Specifies
the name of the index marker type. Useful for Japanese systems,
which use a localized name for the index marker. (Defaults to “Index”
if this parameter is missing or set to a null string.)</p></dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>ExternalApplications section</dt>
<dd><p><indexterm>EPUBReaderAppExe, INI parameter</indexterm><b>EPUBReaderAppExe</b> -
Registers the path and filename of the AZARDI EPUB reader application
to use if an EPUB file is specified in the DitaFMxGuide or DitaReference
parameters. (This feature is considered experimental.)</p></dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>BuildFile section</dt>
<dd><p><indexterm>AntCommand, INI parameter</indexterm><b>AntCommand</b> -
Specifies the command or path/command used to run Ant. The default
is “ant”, but if you need to specify another executable or if you
need to include the path, change this value. This value is used
for both Generate Output options, Current File and Selected Target.
(Defaults to “ant” if this parameter is missing or set to a null
string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>EnvironmentSetup, INI parameter</indexterm><b>EnvironmentSetup</b> -
Specifies a batch file to run before the Ant script in order to
set up any needed environment variables. This parameter can be set
through the DITA-FMx Options dialog in the External Application
Settings dialog. (No default value, must be set to use the Generate
Output command.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>DitaDir, INI parameter</indexterm><b>DitaDir</b> -
Specifies the folder that contains the DITA-OT files. This parameter can
be set through the DITA-FMx Options dialog in the External Application Settings
dialog. (No default value, must be set to use the Generate Output command.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>EnvironmentSetup-BUILD, INI parameter</indexterm><b>EnvironmentSetup-&lt;buildname></b> -
Specifies an alternate batch file to override the default specified
by EnvironmentSetup. Allows you to define builds that rely on different
DITA environments.</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>DitaDir-BUILD, INI parameter</indexterm><b>DitaDir-&lt;buildname></b> -
Specifies an alternate location for the DITA-OT folder to override
the default specified by DitaDir. Allows you to define builds that
rely on different DITA environments.</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>AntScript, INI parameter</indexterm><b>AntScript</b> -
Specifies the filename of the Ant script that is run for the Generate Output:
Current File option. The default is “ditafmx-ant.xml”, but if you
need to specify another filename, change this value. This filename
is assumed to be relative to the path specified by the <i>DitaDir</i> parameter.
(Defaults to “ditafmx-ant.xml” if this parameter is missing or set
to a null string.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>Count (BuildFile), INI parameter</indexterm><b>Count</b> and <b><i>N</i></b> -
Specifies the number of build options available in the <i>AntScript</i> file
(and thus displayed in the Generate Output: Current File output
option). If you modify the targets in that script, be sure to update
the <i>Count</i> value and add/remove the related <i>N</i> value.</p></dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>AntBuild section</dt>
<dd><p><indexterm>Count (AntBuild), INI parameter</indexterm><b>Count</b> and <b><i>N</i></b> -
Specifies the number of “ANT:” sections which define the available
build options displayed in the Generate Output: Selected Target
output option. For each “ANT:” section added, you must update the <i>Count</i> value
and add/remove the related <i>N</i> value. The value of each <i>N</i> parameter
must exactly match the text following the “ANT:” section name.</p></dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>ANT:&lt;buildname> section</dt>
<dd><p><indexterm>BuildFile, INI parameter</indexterm><b>BuildFile</b> -
Specifies path and filename of the associated Ant script (use double backslashes
as the directory delimiter). (No default value, must be set to use the
Selected Target option of the Generate Output command.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>EnvironmentSetup (ANT), INI parameter</indexterm><b>EnvironmentSetup</b> -
Specifies a batch file to run before the Ant script in order to
set up any needed environment variables.</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>Target, INI parameter</indexterm><b>Target</b> -
Specifies target within the <i>BuildFile</i>. (No default value,
must be set to use the Selected Target option of the Generate Output
command.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>OutputDir, INI parameter</indexterm><b>OutputDir</b> -
Specifies the path to the output directory (use double backslashes as
the directory delimiter). (No default value, must be set to use
the Selected Target option of the Generate Output command.)</p></dd>
<dd><p><indexterm>Logfile, INI parameter</indexterm><b>Logfile</b> -
Specifies the path and filename to the log file (use double backslashes as
the directory delimiter). (No default value, must be set to use
the Selected Target option of the Generate Output command.)</p></dd></dlentry></dl></body></topic>
