<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "id0853I010AHS"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>FrameMaker 7.2 Installation Requirements</title>
<shortdesc>If installing on FrameMaker 7.2 and other DITA support
is installed, you will need to disable that DITA support.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>test</author>
<critdates><created date = "UNK"/>
<revised modified = "2014-04-13"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p status = "changed">If you are upgrading from the Adobe
DITA App Pack or from the first beta version of DITA-FMx (v.0.01),
you may need to modify the <filepath>maker.ini</filepath> file or
disable existing client plugins. If you’re new to DITA authoring
or haven’t installed either of these plugins, proceed to <xref href
= "ditafmx_installing_installer.xml#id078AA400U5Z" type = "topic"
format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref>.</p>
<note type = "important">The structure applications provided with
DITA-FMx 2.0 are in FM8 format. FM7.2 users will need to open them
in FM8 and downsave to FM7 format. If you’re unable to do this,
contact Leximation.</note>
<p>In order to eliminate any possible conflicts with previous versions
of the DITA authoring plugins, check the following:</p>
<ul status = "changed"><li><p>Verify that there are no “ditafm”
or “ditafmx” plugin DLLs in the <filepath>FrameMaker/fminit/Plugins</filepath> folder
(or any subfolders). Files to look for are: <filepath>ditafm.dll</filepath>, <filepath>ditafm_app_72.dll</filepath>, <filepath>fm-ditabook.dll</filepath>, <filepath>ditafmx_72.dll</filepath>,
and <filepath>ditafmx_app_72.dll</filepath>. If any of these files
are found, move them to a backup location outside of the <filepath>Plugins</filepath> folder.</p><p>This
only applies to files in the “Plugins” folder; files found in the <filepath>\fminit\ditafm</filepath> folder
can be left alone.</p><note type = "important">Do not rename the
DLLs or move them to a sub-folder of the Plugins folder. You must
completely move them to an alternate location. If the files exist
(under any name) within or below the Plugins folder, FrameMaker
will still load them.</note></li>
<li><p>Open the <filepath>maker.ini</filepath> file and locate the
APIClients section. Look for lines that start with “ditafm” or “ditafm_app”
and delete or comment them out (by adding a semicolon at the start
of the line). Lines that start with “ditafmx” or “ditafmx_app” will
be updated by the installer and do not need to be commented out.</p></li></ul>
<p>You may now proceed to <xref href = "ditafmx_installing_installer.xml#id078AA400U5Z"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref>.</p></body></topic>
