<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="BookBuildOverrides"?><?dtall dict="BreakToInline"?><?dtall
dict="placement=’break"?><?dtall dict="placement=’inline"?><topic
    id = "idd23c490c-4441-4e76-968f-91bbae5af1dd"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Support for Indented Images</title>
<shortdesc>Images are typically aligned with the text margins, but
you can enable the ability for images to align with the container
paragraph.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>test</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-02-28"/>
<revised modified = "2014-04-13"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "changed"><p status = "new"><indexterm status = "new">images<indexterm
status = "new">indented</indexterm></indexterm><indexterm status
= "new">indented images</indexterm><indexterm status = "new">image<indexterm
status = "new">anchoring position</indexterm></indexterm><indexterm
status = "new">image<indexterm status = "new">placement</indexterm></indexterm>The
image/@placement attribute controls the anchoring position of images.
By default, when inserting an <synph outputclass = "element">image</synph> without
a <synph outputclass = "element">fig</synph> container, the <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">placement</synph> attribute will be
set to “inline” (since this would typically be used for inline images). When
inserting an <synph outputclass = "element">image</synph> within
a <synph outputclass = "element">fig</synph> (inserting the <synph
    outputclass = "element">fig</synph> typically automatically
inserts the <synph outputclass = "element">image</synph>), the <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">placement</synph> attribute will be
set to “break”. You are free to change the @placement value as needed
for situations that require a different setting. When <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">placement</synph> is set to “inline”
the anchoring position (<menucascade status = "new">
<uicontrol status = "new">Special</uicontrol><uicontrol status = "new">Anchored
Frame</uicontrol></menucascade>) is set to “At Insertion Point”,
and when <synph outputclass = "attribute">placement</synph> is set
to “break” the anchoring position is set to “Below Current Line”
(these settings cannot be changed).</p>
<p status = "new">When <synph outputclass = "attribute">placement</synph> is
“break” and <synph outputclass = "attribute">align</synph> is “left”,
the image will be forced to the left margin (page margin or side
head margin). If you are using side heads this is typically the
formatting that’s needed, but if you’re not using side heads or
when you have an image in indented text (like a list), you will
probably want the image to be indented to match the text block.</p>
<p status = "new"><indexterm status = "new">BreakToInline, INI parameter</indexterm>If
you make use of the “Move Figure Title” book-build option, you will
find that setting the <synph outputclass = "attribute">placement</synph> of
an <synph outputclass = "element">image</synph> within a <synph
    outputclass = "element">fig</synph> to “inline” will probably achieve
the desired result by allowing the <synph outputclass = "element">image</synph> to
align with the containing paragraph. To automate this processing,
DITA-FMx provides the “BreakToInline” parameter in the BookBuildOverrides
section of the book-build INI file (<filepath status = "new">ditafmx-bookbuild.ini</filepath>).
Setting this parameter to “1” will change all of the <codeph>placement=’break’</codeph> images
to <codeph>placement=’inline’</codeph> that are in a paragraph whose first
indent is greater than zero. This setting must be made manually
in the book-build INI file, and may not work well in all situations,
so it’s best to experiment a bit and test to make sure it is providing
the proper results.</p>
<p>In order for this to work properly, the “Fixed” option of the
“Line Spacing” property of the fig.anchor paragraph (or the style
assigned to a figure anchor) style must be deselected. Also, the
MoveFigTitles book-build INI parameter must be set to “1”. When
testing this, be sure to watch the report in the console log to
verify that you see the following message:</p>
<screen>Using BookBuild Override: BreakToInline=1</screen></body></topic>
