<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "id082AE0V025Z"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Ditaval Manager</title>
<shortdesc status = "changed">Create and edit ditaval files, and
manage the list of ditaval files registered with DITA-FMx.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates status = "changed"><created date = "UNK"/>
<revised modified = "2015-03-29"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p>DITA-FMx provides three commands (<uicontrol>Generate Book
from Map</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Generate Output</uicontrol>, and <uicontrol>Apply
Ditaval</uicontrol>) from which you select from a list of ditaval
files available to DITA-FMx. The Ditaval Manager controls the files
on this list, registered with DITA-FMx. Each ditaval file has an
associated name that is displayed in the lists. By default, this
name is the ditaval file name, but can be changed if needed.</p>
<fig audience = "web"><title>DITA-FMx Ditaval Manager dialog box</title><image
href="images/ditavalmanager.png" align="left" placement="break"
 otherprops = "fmdpi:110"/></fig>
<p>If you have existing ditaval files that you want to use with
DITA-FMx, choose the Add button and select the file. Once it has
been added to the list in the Ditaval Manager dialog, this file
will be available to the other commands that make use of ditaval
files. Use the Rename button to change the name that is shown in
the list (this does not change the actual ditaval file name). The
Remove button will remove a name from the list and can optionally
delete the file as well. You can also use the Add button to create
a new ditaval file and add it to the list.</p>
<p status = "changed">The contents of the currently selected ditaval
file displays in the Ditaval File Entries list in the dialog. Selecting
a <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">prop</synph> element
makes the attributes of that element available for editing. Only <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">prop</synph> elements
can be edited through this dialog, but all elements (as well as
comments) will be shown in the list. After selecting a <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">prop</synph> element,
change the values of the att and val attributes as needed, then
choose the Save To File button to write your changes back to the
ditaval file.</p>
<p status = "changed">Use the Add <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">prop</synph> button to add a new empty
prop element to the file, and the Update <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">prop</synph> button to update the attribute
values of the selected entry in the list based on the values in
the text boxes. The Delete Entry button deletes the currently selected
entry.</p>
<p status = "changed"><indexterm>ditaval</indexterm><indexterm>sample
file</indexterm>The following code shows a simple ditaval file.
Each <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">prop</synph> element
has three attributes. The att and val attributes specify the filtering
attribute and its value to match on. Valid values for the action
attribute are “exclude” and “flag.” This file specifies two filtering
schemes, the first excludes all elements whose audience attribute
has the value of “admin” and the second excludes all elements whose
product attribute has the value of “PROD1.”</p>
<codeblock outputclass = "xml">&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
&lt;val> 
  &lt;prop att="audience" val="admin" action="exclude"/> 
  &lt;prop att="product" val="PROD1" action="exclude"/> 
&lt;/val></codeblock></body></topic>
