<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "id085HG700Y5Z"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Extending DITA-FMx</title>
<shortdesc>Provides methods for controlling DITA-FMx from other
applications.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-05-17"/>
<revised modified = "2015-09-08"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p status = "changed">DITA-FMx provides a limited set of “CallClient”
function calls. These functions can be used by other FDK plugin
clients as well as by ExtendScript (in FM10 and later), FrameScript
and FrameAC.</p>
<note status = "changed">Most of these functions are enabled only
when the “FMx-Auto” addon is installed. For information on this
DITA-FMx addon, please contact Leximation.</note>
<p>A typical syntax statement shows the call from an FDK client
using the F_ApiCallClient() function. A similar call can be made
from ExtendScript or FrameScript using the CallClient() function.</p>
<p status = "changed">All calls require the DITA-FMx client name
(“ditafmx”), which must be lower case, and a call client function
name (which is not case sensitive). Some calls may have additional
(required or optional) parameters. When additional parameters are provided,
they are passed as a single tab or vertical bar delimited string.
If this string exceeds 512 characters it is truncated.</p>
<p>For example, the FixBookRefs call can make use of the bookId.
To pass the bookId (an integer value) convert it to a string and
concatenate that string to the initial parameter. For example, if
the bookId is 3489237, the FDK call would be as follows:</p>
<codeblock status = "changed">F_ApiCallClient("ditafmx", "FixBookRefs\t3489237");</codeblock>
<p status = "new">You can also use the vertical bar character as
the argument delimiter for calls to the ditafmx client:</p>
<codeblock status = "changed">F_ApiCallClient("ditafmx", "FixBookRefs|3489237");</codeblock>
<p status = "changed">If you would like to have access to specific
DITA-FMx functionality that is not currently exposed, please let
us know.</p></body></topic>
