<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="MapFromOutlineTemplate"?><?dtall dict="NewMapShortcuts"?><?dtall
dict="NewTopicShortcuts"?><?dtall dict="STRUCTDIR\xml\DITA"?><topic
    id = "id067FF600BY4"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>New DITA File</title>
<shortdesc>Creates a new DITA map or topic file.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>test</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-02-05"/>
<revised modified = "2015-09-13"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "changed"><p status = "changed">There are two groups
of items on the <menucascade><uicontrol>DITA-FMx</uicontrol><uicontrol>New
DITA File</uicontrol></menucascade> menu. Items above the divider
create a new map file and items below the divider create a new topic
file. The number and label text of these items will vary depending
on the map and topic structure applications you have selected in
the Options dialog. Any element definition that defines a class
attribute with a default value that contains “map/map” will be considered
a “map” and any with a default value that contains “topic/topic” are
considered a “topic.”</p>
<fig><title>New DITA File menu</title><image href="images/newfile-menu.png"
align="left" placement="break"  outputclass = "fmdpi:110"/></fig>
<p status = "new">Each topic or map type is assigned a keyboard
shortcut, if you want to define your own shortcut for specific topic
types, see the information on the NewMapShortcuts and NewTopicShortcuts
parameters in <xref href = "ditafmx_ref_inionly.xml#id067FF8008E9"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local" status = "new"></xref>.</p>
<p status = "changed"><indexterm>map from outline template</indexterm>At
the bottom of the “map” area is the command <uicontrol>New ‘Map
from Outline’ Template</uicontrol>. This command creates a new FM
file using the “Map from Outline” file as the template. By default,
this template is named <filepath>map-from-outline_template.fm</filepath> and is
in the root of the DITA-FMx structure application folder ($STRUCTDIR\xml\DITA-FMx_1.2\).
You can specify an alternate template file by changing the MapFromOutlineTemplate
parameter in the INIOnly section of the <filepath>ditafmx.ini</filepath> file.
For more information, see <xref href = "ditafmx_ref_listtomap.xml#id0824H0ZL05Z"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref> and <xref
href = "ditafmx_ref_inionly.xml#id067FF8008E9" type = "topic" format
= "dita" scope = "local"></xref>.</p>
<p status = "new">Choosing one of the <uicontrol status = "new">New
&lt;ELEMNAME></uicontrol> menu items displays the New DITA File dialog.
This dialog provides fields for entering the topic or map title,
the topic ID, the file name, file path, and an optional <ph conref
= "ditafmx_shared.xml#common/elem-template"></ph> to insert predefined
structure and content into the new file.</p>
<fig audience = "web"><title>DITA-FMx New DITA File dialog box</title><image
href="images/newfile.png" align="left" placement="break"  otherprops
= "fmdpi:110"/></fig>
<p status = "changed">For new topics, the title is inserted into
the first title element, for maps, the title text is entered as
the map/@title attribute or in the map/title element (depending
on the DITA version). The file name field is populated based on
the value of the New File Name Format setting (in Options: New File
Options). If the new file name format includes a building block
that includes the title, the file name field will update as you enter
text into the title field.</p>
<p>Entering a folder name into the File Name field will create the
new file in the specified folder. If that folder, or folders, do
not exist, you will be prompted to allow them to be created.</p>
<note type = "tip">You can use building blocks to automatically
create new files in folders based on the topic type. For an example,
see the <xref href = "ditafmx_ref_newfileoptions.xml#id0824II0E05Z"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref> topic.</note>
<p>You can also select the <uicontrol>Wrap in Dita Element</uicontrol> option
to create a topic file that includes the dita element as the root
element. This is useful if you are creating files with nested topics,
and required if you want to have multiple top-level sibling topics. The
default value for this option is defined in the <uicontrol>New File
Options</uicontrol> dialog.</p>
<p status = "changed">When you choose OK, the file is immediately
saved as XML using the name specified. If you don’t provide a file
name extension for the new topic file, one is added based on the
type specified in the Default File Type option in the Options dialog.
DITA map files are always given the extension of “ditamap.”</p>
<p status = "changed">When creating a new topic or map file, if
your insertion point is in a DITA map at a location that is valid
for a topicref-based element, a dialog displays asking for the type
of element to insert, or none (to not insert as an element).</p>
<p>Creation of new DITA files differs from the standard FrameMaker
“New” command because FrameMaker does not provide a method for creating
an “Untitled” XML file (one that is not saved to the file system).
If you want to start with an “Untitled” file, select the standard
New command (<menucascade><uicontrol>File</uicontrol><uicontrol>New</uicontrol></menucascade>)
and use the DITA template as the template file.</p></body></topic>
