<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="URLs"?><?dtall dict="XrefElements"?><topic
    id = "id067FF6080YK"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Using the Reference Manager</title>
<shortdesc>Lets you select a conref, xref, or link target by specifying
the file, element type, and element.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "2009-02-12"/>
<revised modified = "2014-04-01"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "new"><p status = "new"><indexterm status = "new">inserting
references</indexterm><indexterm status = "new">xrefs, inserting</indexterm><indexterm
status = "new">conrefs, inserting</indexterm><indexterm status =
"new">links, inserting</indexterm>The <wintitle status = "new">Reference
Manager</wintitle> is displayed when inserting a conref, <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">xref</synph>, or <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">link</synph>. To insert
a conref, choose <uicontrol>Insert Conref</uicontrol> from the DITA
menu, to insert an <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">xref</synph> or <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">link</synph>, use the <wintitle
    status = "new">Element Catalog</wintitle>. Note that the <wintitle
    status = "new">Reference Manager</wintitle> is only displayed for <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">xref</synph> or <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">link</synph> elements
if they are defined as a “Container” rather than a “Cross-Reference”
element in your EDD.</p>
<fig status = "new"><title>DITA-FMx Reference Manager</title><image
href="" align="left" placement="break"  keyref = "refman-image"
otherprops = "fmdpi:110"/></fig>
<p status = "changed">To insert a reference of any kind, first specify
the file that contains the reference source. To select a source
file, specify the file location using the File Location list. This
list will initially only contain the label “Files Currently Open
in FrameMaker” but you can browse through files on disk (without
opening them first), by choosing the “F” button (select folder)
or the “M” button (select map).</p>
<p status = "new">Selecting “Files Currently Open in FrameMaker”
will display those files in the Source File list. Selecting the
“F” or “M” buttons will list all “.xml” and “.dita” files in that folder
or map. If you want to place a reference to a file that is not open,
use the Browse button (“...”) to open another file.</p>
<p status = "new">By default the Element Tag list displays only
elements that have id attribute values in the source file. For conrefs,
this list is further restricted by displaying only elements that
are valid at the current insertion point. If you want to limit the
xref or link targets to a specific list of elements, use the XrefElements
parameter in the <filepath conref = "ditafmx_shared.xml#common/ditafm-ini"
class = "+ topic/ph sw-d/filepath "></filepath> file (for details,
see <xref href = "ditafmx_ref_inionly.xml#id067FF8008E9" type =
"topic" format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref>). When you select
an element tag name from the list, the available target elements
display in the Element Data list. By default, only elements that
have an ‘id’ value are available, but if you select the Show All
Elements option, you will be able to select from all available elements
of the selected type (this option is only available if the “Files
Currently Open in FrameMaker” file location is selected).</p>
<p status = "new">The elements are listed with their ‘id’ and textual
content. To place the reference, select an element and choose the
Insert button. If you have selected an element that does not have
an ‘id’ value, you will be prompted to provide an ‘id’ for that
element (the ‘id’ is written to the source file, so be sure to save
that file before exiting). If you want to specify text for the xref
that is different than that of the target element, enter that text
in the Alternate Xref Text field. To insert an xref to an external
file, choose the External Xref button.</p>
<p status = "new">To insert a reference based on a key, choose the
Key Reference button (or enter the key value in the Key Reference
field). The Keyref Manager dialog allows you to select a key from
the specified keyspace, then optionally select an element within
the file referenced by that key. When placing an xref or link to
the root topic in a file, it is only necessary to provide the key
name. When inserting a conref, you should provide the key and the
sub-element reference.</p>
<fig audience = "web print" status = "new"><title>DITA-FMx Keyref
Manager dialog</title><image href="images/keyref-manager-xref.png"
align="left" placement="break"  otherprops = "fmdpi:110"/></fig>
<p status = "new">When inserting a conref, the Alternate Xref Text
field is replaced with a Conref End list. This is populated with
valid conref end targets based on your selection in the Element
Data list.</p>
<fig audience = "web print" status = "new"><title>DITA-FMx Reference
Manager dialog - conref insertion</title><image href="images/refmanager-conref.png"
align="left" placement="break"  otherprops = "fmdpi:110"/></fig>
<p status = "new">If you double-click a conref or xref, the <wintitle
    status = "new">Reference Manager</wintitle> displays with the
current reference selected. Choosing the Replace button inserts
a new reference using the selected criteria in place of the old
reference.</p>
<note status = "new">Replacing an existing reference removes any
existing locally applied attribute data.</note>
<p>Conrefs are inserted as a locked range of text (like a text inset)
and are tagged with the “DITA-Conref” color. By default this color
is defined as blue, but because it is defined in the template, you
can change it to suit your needs.</p>
<p>Xrefs and links are also inserted as a locked range of text,
but no coloring or formatting is applied other than that specified
by your structure application (EDD or template). When an xref or
link is created or modified, the type attribute is set to the name
of the target element, the format attribute is set to “dita,” and
the scope attribute is set to “local.”</p>
<note type = "tip">If you’d like more of the title text visible
in the Reference Manager, enable the “Use Wide Reference Manager”
option in the DITA-FMx Options dialog.</note>
<section id = "id067FF60G0HT" status = "new"><title>External Xref</title><p
    status = "changed">Choose the External Xref button in the Reference
Manager dialog to insert an <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">xref</synph> or <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">link</synph> that references files outside
of the documentation set. Specify the target (the href attribute
value) and the link text (the content of the <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">xref</synph> or <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">link</synph> element), as well as the
value for the scope attribute (“external” or “peer”).</p><p
    status = "new">For URLs, set the scope value to “external”.
The format attribute is automatically set to “html” for references
of this type.</p><fig audience = "web print"><title>DITA-FMx External
Xref dialog box</title><image href="images/externalxref.png" align="left"
placement="break"  otherprops = "fmdpi:110"/></fig><p status = "new">If
you are creating an <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">xref</synph> or <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">link</synph> to other
types of non-DITA content use the browse button (“...”) to select
the file or enter the path and file name in the href field. When
using the browse button, the link text will be set to the target
file name, you are free to change it to whatever is needed. The
format attribute is set to the value of the file extension.</p><fig
    audience = "web print"><title>DITA-FMx External Xref dialog
box</title><image href="images/externalxref-peer.png" align="left"
placement="break"  otherprops = "fmdpi:110"/></fig><p status = "new">Keep
in mind that it is your responsibility to make sure that the path
in the href field is accurate for the “published” document. Just
because you use the browse button to select a file that exists while
authoring, doesn’t mean that this same path is valid for the published
environment. Paths to external references (“external” or “peer”) are
not validated during the DITA-FMx book build or other publishing
processes.</p><p status = "new">Once an external reference has been
created you can modify it by double-clicking the xref.</p></section></body></topic>
