<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "id085HGE040Y4"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>FixBookRefs</title>
<shortdesc>Normalizes all references in the files of a FM book file.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-05-17"/>
<revised modified = "2015-03-31"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p>Use this function to rebuild and correct all references
(xrefs, links, conrefs, and image references) after aggregating
loose DITA topics into “chapter” files. Call this function using
the “FixBookRefs” parameter to update the active book, or pass the <varname>bookIdOrName</varname> value
(as a string) after this parameter to update a specific book. In order
to properly update the references in the book, the fm-ditabook/@href
attribute must be set to the map’s path and file name. You can set
this attribute before calling FixBookRefs, or you can pass this
value as the <varname>mapFile</varname> parameter.</p>
<section id = "id085HGH00RHT"><title>Syntax</title><codeblock status = "changed">F_ApiCallClient("ditafmx", "FixBookRefs [[|<varname>bookIdOrName</varname>] |<varname>mapFile</varname>]");</codeblock><dl>
<dlentry><dt><varname>bookIdOrName</varname></dt>
<dd>The id or path and file name of the book to process. The book
must be open. You must use double backslashes as the directory delimiter
when specifying the book file name. Optional; if not provided the
“active” book is used, must be provided if <varname>mapFile</varname> is
used.</dd></dlentry></dl><dl><dlentry><dt><varname>mapFile</varname></dt>
<dd status = "changed">The path and file name of the DITA map from
which the book was generated. You must use double backslashes as
the directory delimiter when specifying the DITA map file name.
Optional; if not provided the fm-ditabook/@href attribute must be
set to the value of the map’s path and file name before calling FixBookRefs.
If this parameter is used, the <varname>bookIdOrName</varname> parameter
is required.</dd></dlentry></dl><note conref = "ditafmx_shared.xml#common/fmxapi_auto"
status = "changed"></note></section>
<section><title>Return Value</title><dl compact = "yes"><dlentry><dt>0</dt>
<dd>Failure. Unable to update the specified book. It is also possible
that DITA-FMx is not available for calls. Verify that DITA-FMx is
registered in the <filepath>maker.ini</filepath> file using the
client name of “ditafmx”.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>-1</dt>
<dd>Failure. <varname>bookIdOrName</varname> is not a structured
book.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>-2</dt>
<dd>Failure. No non-generated files in book.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>>0</dt>
<dd>Successfully updated the specified book (this is the id of the
book processed).</dd></dlentry></dl></section></body></topic>
