<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "id082590WN0HT"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Creating Element Templates</title>
<shortdesc>Provides a method to add predefined structure and content
to new files.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-02-05 @ 09:33 (scottp)"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-29"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p><indexterm>element template</indexterm>An element template
is an FM binary file that contains structural and textual content that
is inserted into a new topic when it is created. You can have many
different element templates for each topic type. Available element
templates may be selected in the New DITA File dialog.</p>
<p>By default, element templates are stored in the folder that contains
the structure application template file. You can specify another
folder (local or network location) to store these files in the New
File Options dialog which is available from the New DITA File dialog
or the Options dialog.</p>
<p>Element template files must follow a strict naming convention
in order to appear in the list in the New DITA File dialog. The
file name pattern is <filepath>new~&lt;topictype>~&lt;template name>.fm</filepath>.
That is “new” followed by a tilde followed by the topic or map element
type (such as “topic”, “concept”, “task” etc.), followed by a tilde, followed
by the name that you want to appear in the list, with an “.fm” file
extension.</p>
<p>To create an element template just create a new DITA file and
insert the elements and content that you want in the template, then
save this file to a binary FM file into the specified element template
folder. Note that when the new file is created using your template,
the text of the title element will be replaced with the text entered
in the New DITA File dialog, and the ID attribute of the root topic
will be replaced with a new unique ID (assuming that the “auto-add
IDs” option is enabled in Options).</p>
<p>Sample topic and task element templates are provided in the DITA-FMx
Topic application folder.</p></body></topic>
