<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "id0853H0GE05Z"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Xref to Hyperlink</title>
<shortdesc>Builds FrameMaker Hyperlinks at each <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">xref</synph> or <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">link</synph> element, to enable live hyperlinks
in generated PDF files.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "UNK"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-29"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p status = "changed">By default, only <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">fm-xref</synph> or <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">fm-link</synph> elements become “live”
hyperlinks in a PDF generated from FrameMaker (as opposed to a PDF
generated through the DITA-OT with the <uicontrol>Generate Output</uicontrol> command).
Run the <uicontrol>Xref to Hyperlink</uicontrol> command on an FM
file or book to build hyperlinks from each <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">xref</synph> or <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">link</synph> element. This command only
processes “internal” <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">xref</synph> and <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">link</synph> elements
(those where the scope attribute is set to something other than
“external”). To ensure that external xrefs or links become live
hyperlinks, you must enable the <uicontrol>Add Hypertext Marker to
External Xrefs</uicontrol> option in the Options dialog before generating
the FM file or book.</p>
<p>In order to create proper “gotolink” Hypertext commands, associated
Hypertext markers with “newlink” commands are inserted at each element
that contains an id attribute.</p>
<p>This command should be run only on generated FM files, not the
source XML files. Running this command on XML files results in the
Hypertext markers being saved to the XML as processing instructions
and needlessly clutters the files.</p>
<p>This can also be done automatically during the Map to Book conversion
process by selecting the <uicontrol>Convert Xrefs/Links into Hyperlinks</uicontrol> option
in the <wintitle>Book Build Settings</wintitle> dialog found in
the <wintitle>DITA Options</wintitle> dialog.</p></body></topic>
