<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "id95151bba-5c40-459f-8f98-f943fbcd3ac5"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Element Mapping</title>
<shortdesc>Allows the specification of simpletable element types
and preformatted element types. Any specializations of these element
types should be added here.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "UNK"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-31"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p>The Element Mapping dialog lists the default and specialized
elements that are processed in a particular way by DITA-FMx.</p>
<fig audience = "web"><title>DITA-FMx Element Mapping dialog box</title><image
href="images/elementmapping.png" align="left" placement="break"
 otherprops = "fmdpi:110"/></fig>
<p>When <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">simpletable</synph>-based
elements are encountered during the import process, FrameMaker needs
to be able to count the number of columns in each table. This information
is typically stored in attributes within the table element, but
the DITA specification does not provide this type of attribute for <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">simpletable</synph>s
(and any table based on a <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">simpletable</synph>). </p>
<p status = "new">Using the information provided in this dialog,
FrameMaker can determine the number of columns in these tables.
The default <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">simpletable</synph> elements
are indicated with an asterisk. Even though the <synph status = "new"
    outputclass = "element">choicetable</synph> elements are specialized from <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">simpletable</synph>,
they are not listed in this dialog because they must always have
two columns and are therefore defined in the read/write rules file.</p>
<p>If you’ve specialized <synph status = "new" outputclass = "element">simpletable</synph> to
create one of your own, you’ll need to add it to this list. Enter
the table, row, and cell element names in the fields provided. If your
table uses different element names for the cells (like the <synph
    status = "new" outputclass = "element">properties</synph> table), you
can enter the multiple names separated by the vertical bar character.</p></body></topic>
