<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [
]>
<?dtall dict="admin"?><?dtall dict="apps\\DITA"?><?dtall dict="Files\Adobe\FrameMaker\DITA"?><?dtall
dict="STRUCTDIR\\xml\\DITA"?><?dtall dict="XSLTProcessors"?><concept
    id = "idb62f0002-1e12-400f-a28a-a48ed67fcda7"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Special Instructions for FM12 and Earlier</title>
<shortdesc status = "changed">With the FM13.0.1 update, the default
XSLT processor changed to SAXON. This requires some extra work when
setting up the Book structure application for installations on FM12
and earlier.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "2015-09-10"/>
<revised modified = "2019-03-14"/></critdates></prolog>
<conbody><p status = "changed">The DITA-FMx Book structure application
makes use of an XSLT import script (<filepath status = "new">bookmap2fmbook.xsl</filepath>)
to aggregate the topic files in the map. There are two versions
of this XSLT script, one that requires the XALAN processor and one
that requires SAXON. Because the default XSLT processor since FM
2015 is SAXON, that’s the version that is set up as the default.</p>
<p status = "new">If you’re installing DITA-FMx on FM12 or earlier,
you’ll need to copy the XALAN version of this script over the default
XSLT file because XALAN is the default XSLT processor on those versions
of FrameMaker.</p>
<note status = "new">Technically, if you’re installing on FM 2015
with no updates installed, you’ll also need to use the XALAN version,
but we assume that you’ll be installing the FM updates, so as long
as the FM version is 13.0.1 or greater, you should be fine with the
default SAXON version.</note>
<p status = "new">It is possible to switch the default XSLT processor
on FM12 or FM11 to SAXON, so you may want to do that instead of
using the XALAN version of the script. Also, it is possible to change
the default processor to XALAN on FM 2015 and later.</p>
<p status = "new">To change the default XSLT processor on FM11 and
later:</p>
<ol status = "new"><li status = "new"><p status = "new">Open the <filepath
    status = "new">maker.ini</filepath> file in a text editor and
locate the XSLTProcessors section.</p></li>
<li status = "new"><p status = "new">Move the “<b status = "new">,
Default</b>” parameter (the word “Default” and the leading comma)
to the line that specifies the processor type you want to be the
default.</p></li>
<li status = "new"><p status = "new">Save and close the <filepath
    status = "new">maker.ini</filepath> file then restart FrameMaker.</p></li></ol>
<p status = "new">Once you’ve set the default XSLT processor, locate
the Book structure application folder, and you should see three
similarly named XSLT files:</p>
<ul status = "new"><li><p status = "new"><filepath status = "new">bookmap2fmbook.xsl</filepath></p></li>
<li><p status = "new"><filepath status = "new">bookmap2fmbook-SAXON.xsl</filepath></p></li>
<li><p status = "new"><filepath status = "new">bookmap2fmbook-XALAN.xsl</filepath></p></li></ul>
<p status = "new">Delete the <filepath status = "new">bookmap2fmbook.xsl</filepath> file,
then copy the XSLT file that indicates the processor you want to
use (SAXON or XALAN), to the file name <filepath status = "new">bookmap2fmbook.xsl</filepath>.
Using this technique, you can switch from SAXON to XALAN as needed.</p>
<p status = "new">If you have a custom structure application, you’ll
need to make sure it’s using the proper XSLT file for the default
XSLT processor.</p></conbody></concept>
