<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<?dtall dict="alt"?><?dtall dict="BaselineOffset"?><?dtall dict="fmdpi:&lt;DPI"?><?dtall
dict="pts"?><topic id = "id082SI0K0L5Z"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Working with Images</title>
<shortdesc>Information and tips regarding the image handling features.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<author>test</author>
<critdates><created date = "2008-02-28"/>
<revised modified = "2014-04-12"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "changed"><p status = "changed">To insert an image,
just insert the <synph outputclass = "element">image</synph> or <synph
    outputclass = "element">fig</synph> element from the Element Catalog.
The Insert Image dialog lets you select the image folder location
and the image file name. You can also set the <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">alignment</synph>, <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">placement</synph>, and DPI values.
If the “fmdpi” feature is enabled, the DPI value will be assigned
to that property, otherwise it’ll be used to set the <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">height</synph> and <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">width</synph> attribute values.</p>
<fig><title>Insert Image dialog</title><image href="images/insert-image.png"
align="left" placement="break"  outputclass = "fmdpi:110"><alt>alt
text</alt></image></fig>
<p>Use the “...” (browse) button to add one or more image location
paths to the list. The “X” button deletes the current path from
the list.</p>
<p>Alternatively (or in addition to selecting the file name), you
can specify a key reference to identify the image file. Choose the
Key Reference button to display the Keyref File Browser dialog.
Selecting the keyspace lists all of the keys in that keyspace that
reference files which match the specified file name filter.</p>
<fig><title>Keyref File Browser dialog</title><image href="images/image-keyref.png"
align="left" placement="break"  outputclass = "fmdpi:110"><alt>more
alt text</alt></image></fig>
<p status = "changed"><indexterm>image handling</indexterm><indexterm>images,
shrink-wrapped</indexterm>When an image is added to a document,
the anchored frame is “shrink-wrapped” to the size of the image.
The relative path to the image file is added to the <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">href</synph> attribute and the height/width
in pixels is added to the <synph outputclass = "attribute">height</synph> and <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">width</synph> attributes. The initial
value of the <synph outputclass = "attribute">placement</synph> attribute
matches that specified as the default in the EDD, unless the image
is auto-inserted as the result of inserting a <synph
    outputclass = "element">fig</synph> element in which case the <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">placement</synph> attribute is set
to “break.” For images where the <synph outputclass = "attribute">placement</synph> attribute
value is “break,” the initial alignment is set to match that of
the default value of the <synph outputclass = "attribute">align</synph> attribute
as defined in the EDD; no alignment value is set for “inline” images.</p>
<p>You can change the alignment after inserting the image by editing
the value of the <synph outputclass = "attribute">align</synph> attribute
or by selecting an alignment option in the Anchored Frame dialog (<menucascade>
<uicontrol>Special</uicontrol><uicontrol>Anchored Frame</uicontrol></menucascade>).
The <synph outputclass = "attribute">height</synph> and <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">width</synph> cannot be set through
the attribute value; they can only be changed by re-importing the
image using a different scaling, or by changing the properties through
the Object Properties dialog. The <synph outputclass = "attribute">href</synph> attribute
also cannot be changed through the attribute value.</p>
<p><indexterm>native image size</indexterm><indexterm>image size,
native</indexterm>If you do not want any height/width values associated
with an image, deleting those attributes in the XML or Frame document
will result in the image element being written with no values for <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">height</synph> and <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">width</synph> which uses the “native”
(default) size of the image. This is often desirable for output
being generated as HTML.</p>
<p><indexterm>dpi, image</indexterm><indexterm>image dpi</indexterm><indexterm>fmdpi
setting</indexterm>If you want to use the native size of raster
images for output generated through the Open Toolkit but want to
use a specific DPI for output generated from FrameMaker, add an
“fmdpi:<i>DPI</i>” attribute value to the image/@outputclass attribute,
where <i>DPI</i> is the DPI value. Adding this value to the <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">outputclass</synph> attribute allows
the DPI setting to round trip from XML to Frame and it will only
be used by FrameMaker; other output processes will see no <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">height</synph> and width <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">values</synph> and will use the native
image size. Adding this value to the <synph outputclass = "attribute">outputclass</synph> attribute
deletes any value set to the <synph outputclass = "attribute">height</synph> or <synph
    outputclass = "attribute">width</synph> attributes.</p>
<p status = "changed">If you want to use the fmdpi feature for all
raster images, enable the “Use fmdpi for New Images” setting in
the Authoring Options dialog. This will set the fmdpi value to the
DPI value you select when importing the image. The fmdpi value is
only set for raster images; this feature is not available for vector
images.</p>
<note status = "changed">If your images sizes are not round-tripping
properly, your read/write rules file probably needs to be updated.
Refer to the <xref href = "ditafmx_app_imagesupport.xml#id0837HJ0C05Z"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local" status = "new"></xref> topic
for the proper rules, especially with regard to the height and width
attribute definitions.</note>
<section status = "new"><title>Baseline Offset of Inline Images</title><p
    status = "new"><indexterm status = "new">image, alt text</indexterm><indexterm
status = "new">alt text, images</indexterm><indexterm status = "new">alternative
text</indexterm><indexterm>baseline offset</indexterm><indexterm>inline
images, baseline offset</indexterm>By default, the baseline offset
for inline images is set to 2 pts (this shifts the image 2 pts below
the baseline of the surrounding text). If you want to set this property
to a different value, change the value of the Baseline Offset option
in the Authoring Options dialog. This value is only applied to inline
images. Setting the “baseline offset” property in the read/write
rules file has no effect.</p></section>
<section status = "new"><title>Special Handling of Alternative Text
(image/alt)</title><p status = "new"><indexterm status = "new">image,
alt text</indexterm><indexterm status = "new">alt text, images</indexterm><indexterm
status = "new">alternative text</indexterm>Content of an image/alt
element is stored in the anchored frame’s “object attribute” while
open in FrameMaker. To edit the alt text, select the anchored frame,
then choose <menucascade><uicontrol>Graphics</uicontrol><uicontrol>Object
Properties</uicontrol></menucascade>, then Object Attributes. The <synph
    outputclass = "element">alt</synph> value is stored in the “Alternate”
field.</p><p status = "new">Because a graphic object cannot have
child elements this content is stored in an attribute, any attributes
on the <synph outputclass = "element">alt</synph> element or child
elements are discarded when the file is opened in FrameMaker.</p></section></body></topic>
