<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "id067FF700U7Q"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Generate Output</title>
<shortdesc>Provides methods for generating output through the DITA
Open Toolkit (DITA-OT) from within FrameMaker.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author status = "new">Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates status = "changed"><created date = "2008-02-24"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-31"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p>Select the build type and the desired options, then choose
the Build button to generate output through the DITA Open Toolkit.
If you want to generate output based on the current file (a topic
or map) using one of the pre-defined targets (such as CHM, XHTML,
or PDF), use the Current File option. If you have set up an Ant
script to build a specific project (not necessarily the current
file), use the Selected Target option.</p>
<fig audience = "web"><title>DITA-FMx Generate Output dialog box</title><image
href="images/generateoutput.png" align="left" placement="break"
 otherprops = "fmdpi:110"/></fig>
<dl><dlentry><dt>Current File</dt>
<dd status = "new"><p>This option uses a provided Ant script for
processing the current map or topic file using the selected target.
You can also use the <option>Use Selected Ditaval File</option> option
to specify filtering using a selected ditaval file. For setup information,
see <xref href = "ditafmx_installing_genoutput.xml#id_067EF01A0YZ/id078AF0J0LHS"
type = "section" format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref>.</p><p>When
this build type is used, a folder is created in the current file’s
folder named <filepath class = "+ topic/ph sw-d/filepath ">build-&lt;filename></filepath>.
Within that folder, another folder is created to match the selected
output type. The files are generated in that folder.</p></dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Selected Target</dt>
<dd><p>This option lets you run an Ant script and target that you
have provided. For information on using this feature, see the section <xref
href = "ditafmx_installing_genoutput.xml#id_067EF01A0YZ/id_0679K0GL05Z"
type = "section" format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref>.</p></dd></dlentry></dl>
<p>Additional options are available for use with either Generate
Output build option.</p>
<dl><dlentry><dt id = "id0832H00105Z">Open Output</dt>
<dd>If selected, the output folder will be opened after the build
completes.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Write Logfile</dt>
<dd>If selected, a log file is generated and opened after the build
completes. If this option is not selected, the build status displays
in a command shell window.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Keep Dialog Open</dt>
<dd>If selected, the Generate Output dialog remains open so you
can easily run another build.</dd></dlentry>
<dlentry><dt>Use Selected Ditaval File</dt>
<dd>This option is only available for use with the Current File
output type. If selected, the selected ditaval file is used for
the build. Note that you must have added ditaval files with the
Ditaval Manager in order for ditaval files to be listed here.</dd></dlentry></dl></body></topic>
