<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>
<topic id = "id1086AD00E5Z" status = "new"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Initializing DITA-FMx</title>
<shortdesc status = "new">Request your authorization code and verify
that everything is set up properly.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "UNK"/>
<revised modified = "2014-03-29"/></critdates></prolog>
<body status = "new"><p status = "new">After you’ve run the DITA-FMx
installer and set up the structure applications, there are a couple
things that you may need to do before you’re ready to use DITA-FMx.</p>
<p status = "new"><indexterm status = "new">authorization code</indexterm><indexterm
status = "new">auth code</indexterm><indexterm status = "new">trial
auth code</indexterm>If you are new to DITA-FMx, you’ll need to
request an authorization code. For a 30-day trial authorization
code, choose the <menucascade status = "new"><uicontrol status = "new">DITA-FMx</uicontrol>
<uicontrol status = "new">Unregistered. Try Now?</uicontrol></menucascade> menu
item (near the bottom of the menu). Follow the on-screen instructions
and enter your email address on leximation.com. Your trial authorization
code will be sent to the email address you provide. If your trial
authorization code has expired and you need more time, just contact
us by email and we’ll be happy to provide an extension.</p>
<p status = "new">If you’ve purchased DITA-FMx, your permanent authorization
code is available in your Tool Administration area on leximation.com.
Just log on to leximation.com, then click the “Tool Administration”
link in the lower left of any page. On this page you should see
an entry for DITA-FMx with a “request auth code” link. Click that
link and your auth code will be sent to the email address registered
to your leximation.com account.</p>
<p status = "new">Once you get your authorization code (trial or
permanent), select the <menucascade status = "new">
<uicontrol status = "new">DITA-FMx</uicontrol>
<uicontrol status = "new">Enter Authorization Code</uicontrol></menucascade> menu
item and provide the information requested. This should unlock the
items in the DITA-FMx menu.</p>
<p status = "new">Now you should verify that the proper structure
applications are selected in the DITA Options dialog. Choose <menucascade
    status = "new"><uicontrol status = "new">DITA-FMx</uicontrol>
<uicontrol status = "new">DITA Options</uicontrol></menucascade>.
The Topic, Map, and Book applications should list those that you
want to use. If you’re using the default DITA-FMx applications that
would be DITA-FMx-Topic-1.2, DITA-FMx-Map-1.2, and DITA-FMx-Book-1.2.
If these applications aren’t available in the drop-lists, you should
go back and review the <xref href = "ditafmx_installing_apps.xml#id078AAC00PY4"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local" status = "new"></xref> topic;
if these applications have been properly installed, their names
should be available in the drop-lists in the Options dialog.</p>
<p status = "new">You may also want to set other options at this
time. Use the Help button in the Options dialog to read about the
many options available in DITA-FMx.</p>
<note status = "new"><indexterm status = "new">maintenance license</indexterm><indexterm
status = "new">license, maintenance</indexterm>Updates for DITA-FMx
2.0 are provided on a “maintenance license.” When you purchase DITA-FMx
you get the first year of updates at no additional cost. If you want
to continue to receive updates for another year, you’ll need to
pay for another year of maintenance. If you decide not to extend
your license, you can continue to use the update that was available
during your valid license period. You can always check the state
of your maintenance license by choosing <menucascade status = "new">
<uicontrol status = "new">DITA-FMx</uicontrol>
<uicontrol status = "new">Registered to (YOUR NAME)</uicontrol></menucascade>.</note></body></topic>
