<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [

<!-- Begin Document Specific Declarations -->


<!-- End Document Specific Declarations -->

]>

<?Fm Condition DITA-Topicmeta Red NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Prolog AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Comment AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_SYSTEM_HIDEELEMENT AsIs NO_OVERRIDE hide?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_TRACK_CHANGES_ADDED Forest%20Green SINGLE_UNDERLINE show?>
<?Fm Condition FM8_TRACK_CHANGES_DELETED Red STRIKETHROUGH show?>
<?Fm Condition DITA-Data AsIs NO_OVERRIDE show?>

<?Fm BoolCondExpr "DITA-Data" State 0?>


<?Fm TrackChange Off PreviewState PREVIEW_OFF_TRACK_CHANGE?>
<topic id = "id420ff157-8ac5-4424-afde-ca14e0c135ab"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Merge Para Tags</title>
<shortdesc>Ensures that all paragraph tag names in all currently
open documents, exist in all of those documents.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>Scott Prentice</author>
<critdates><created date = "2011-01-08"/>
<revised modified = "2011-01-08"/></critdates></prolog>
<body><p>This command is useful for making it easier to set up PDF
bookmarks for a PDF created from a book. When creating a PDF from
a book, the bookmark list is the collection of all paragraph styles
in all documents in that book. The include/exclude settings are
defined by the first component in the book. Use the Merge Para Tags
command to ensure that all paragraph tags in all files, exist in
the first document.</p>
<note>This command does not actually “copy” the style definitions,
it just ensures that the tag names are the same. This means that
it should not modify any existing style definitions.</note>
<p>It is best to run this command on the component templates that
are used when building a book from a map, as well as any included
files like a title page. </p>
<p>By default, all open files are updated but are not saved, so
you can decide which ones to save. If you just want to make sure
that the “first” file in the book has all of the styles (usually
the title page), you can just save that file and close the others
without saving.</p></body></topic>
