<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd" [
]>
<?dtall dict="apps"?><?dtall dict="DTDs"?><?dtall dict="Structure\xml"?><?dtall
dict="ditafmx"?><?dtall dict="FrameMaker\DITA"?><concept
    id = "ide861c20d-568d-4b7c-b5aa-d8c1f3f3cae5"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Using Lightweight DITA in DITA-FMx</title>
<shortdesc>Lightweight DITA offers a simpler model for authoring
of content.</shortdesc>
<prolog><author>scottp</author>
<critdates><created date = "UNK"/>
<revised modified = "2017-11-10"/></critdates></prolog>
<conbody><p>As of v.2.0.06, DITA-FMx supports authoring and publishing
of the Lightweight DITA model. While the specification for this
model is not final, it seems stable enough to provide a set of (beta)
structure applications to give users a taste of this alternative authoring
and publishing option.</p>
<p>The structure applications provided with DITA-FMx are based on
the model as of June 2, 2016. Updates to the DTDs are available
on <xref href = "https://github.com/oasis-open/dita-lightweight"
format = "html" scope = "external">github.com</xref>.</p>
<note type = "remember">These structure applications are considered
to be “beta” samples. If you run into problems or have any questions,
please contact us at &lt;<ph audience = "web">ditafmx-help AT leximation
DOT com</ph><xref href = "mailto:ditafmx-help@leximation.com" format
= "html" scope = "external" audience = "help">ditafmx-help@leximation.com</xref>>. </note>
<p>In order to use the Lightweight DITA model, you need to install
the structure applications. We provide the same set of apps as with
the full model, Topic, Map, and Book. These apps are available in <filepath>LwDITA-FMx_apps.zip</filepath> file
found in the DITA-FMx installation folder (<filepath>FrameMaker\DITA-FMx-2</filepath>).
Just extract the contents of that file into your <filepath>Structure\xml</filepath> folder.
This should result in a LwDITA-FMx folder with the application folders
inside.</p>
<fig><title>Lightweight DITA structure applications</title><image
href="images/lwdita-install.png" align="left" placement="break"
 outputclass = "fmdpi:120"/></fig>
<p>Each of the application folders contains a “structapps-stub”
file along with the required application files. Insert the stub
file into your structure application definition file as described
in <xref href = "ditafmx_installing_apps_manual.xml#id078AAC00PY42"
type = "topic" format = "dita" scope = "local"></xref> (using the LwDITA
stub files instead of the default app files). </p>
<p>After installing these applications, set the Book, Topic, and
Map applications to the LwDITA apps in the DITA Options dialog.
Once this is complete, you should be able to create and edit Lightweight
DITA files in FrameMaker.</p>
<p>The <filepath>_readme.txt</filepath> file contains additional
information about Lightweight DITA and the provided structure applications.</p></conbody></concept>
